<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on natehn~</title>
    <link>https://natehn.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on natehn~</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>nathan hewitt Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International (CC BY-NC-SA 4.0)</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://natehn.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Digital Security</title>
      <link>https://natehn.com/posts/digital-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://natehn.com/posts/digital-security/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://natehn.com/abstract-projection-1.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;An abstract video still projected onto my kitchen cabinets.&#34;/&gt; &lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;An abstract video still projected onto my kitchen cabinets.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Over the &lt;a href=&#34;https://natehn.com/posts/2020/#the-world-through-a-screen&#34;&gt;last year and a half&lt;/a&gt; or so I&amp;rsquo;ve learned quite a bit about online security. My interest was sparked by participation with a few different activist groups in 2019-2020 and amazing classes put together by &lt;a href=&#34;https://techlearningcollective.com/&#34;&gt;Tech Learning Collective&lt;/a&gt;, which in turn led to a pretty significant amount of independent research. Along the way I&amp;rsquo;ve had the opportunity to share the basics of what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned through a &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.fracturedatlas.org/security-privacy-tools-artistic-collaboration&#34;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; that &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.artistsguide.to/so-long-substack-and-thanks-for-all/&#34;&gt;flew pretty far&lt;/a&gt; and eventually led to an opportunity to teach an introductory class for &lt;a href=&#34;https://airmedia.org/tools/digital-security-virtual-collaboration-concepts-tools-and-techniques-modern-creative&#34;&gt;folks in independent radio&lt;/a&gt;. These notes are nowhere near an &lt;a href=&#34;https://mshelton.medium.com/current-digital-security-resources-5c88ba40ce5c&#34;&gt;exhaustive list of what&amp;rsquo;s out there&lt;/a&gt;, but I wanted to share some of the knowledge I&amp;rsquo;ve gathered thus far.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;~&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;notes-for-everyone&#34;&gt;Notes for everyone&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No app is perfect, and everyone&amp;rsquo;s individual situation is different. That&amp;rsquo;s where &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Threat_model&#34;&gt;threat modeling&lt;/a&gt; comes in. &lt;a href=&#34;https://ssd.eff.org/en/module/your-security-plan&#34;&gt;Everyone will make different choices&lt;/a&gt; based on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.accessnow.org/cms/assets/uploads/2020/10/A-first-look-at-digital-security-OCT2020.pdf&#34;&gt;the threats they face&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For example, if I&amp;rsquo;m all about security and privacy, why I am I &lt;a href=&#34;https://natehn.com/posts/2020/&#34;&gt;writing all about my life&lt;/a&gt; on a website and sharing about my life via &lt;a href=&#34;https://buttondown.email/natehn&#34;&gt;a newsletter&lt;/a&gt;? It has to do with my own personal situation - I&amp;rsquo;m not a core organizer. I do not hold sensitive information about activist activities at this point. But I do try and keep my data out of Facebook&amp;rsquo;s hands.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A threat that all people in our interconnected global world face is &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Surveillance_capitalism&#34;&gt;surveillance capitalism&lt;/a&gt;. Shoshana Zuboff&amp;rsquo;s interviews with &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2019/jan/20/shoshana-zuboff-age-of-surveillance-capitalism-google-facebook&#34;&gt;The Guardian&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.getrevue.co/profile/themarkup/issues/understanding-the-threat-of-surveillance-capitalism-350921&#34;&gt;The Markup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hIXhnWUmMvw&#34;&gt;VPRO&lt;/a&gt; are a great place to start for information on the topic if you aren&amp;rsquo;t familiar. (Surveillance capitalism &lt;a href=&#34;https://lifehacker.com/everyones-trying-to-track-what-you-do-on-the-web-heres-5887140&#34;&gt;is nothing new&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Surveillance capitalism not only undermines personal privacy, but challenges democratic government at its core.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Data is content, and metadata is context. Metadata can be much more revealing than data, especially when collected in the aggregate.&amp;rdquo; - Bruce Schneier&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Metadata is the &amp;ldquo;surplus&amp;rdquo; data that Google built itself upon and that fuels surveillance capitalism. The Markup&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://themarkup.org/blacklight&#34;&gt;Blacklight&lt;/a&gt; and EFF&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://coveryourtracks.eff.org/&#34;&gt;Cover Your Tracks&lt;/a&gt; can show you the alarming amount of data that companies are collecting about your online activity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As a result, the fact that you might feel &amp;ldquo;anonymous&amp;rdquo; - perhaps you used a fake name when signing up for a forum - does not mean you your activities are private or secure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The idea that there are tools that would always work for everyone, everywhere; require no extra knowledge and zero additional infrastructure; are fair and just, and protect users at all times, is a dream that has not yet come true.&amp;rdquo; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://tacticaltech.org/#/news/technology-is-stupid&#34;&gt;Tactical Tech&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;7&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you want to limit surveillance capitalists&amp;rsquo; influence on your life, start by using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/new/&#34;&gt;Firefox&lt;/a&gt; (or if a novice Chrome user, &lt;a href=&#34;https://brave.com/&#34;&gt;Brave&lt;/a&gt;) rather than Google Chrome. Google was the original surveillance capitalist company. Then add in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gorhill/uBlock/&#34;&gt;uBlock Origin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://privacybadger.org/&#34;&gt;Privacy Badger&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://decentraleyes.org/&#34;&gt;Decentraleyes&lt;/a&gt; browser add-ons. Make sure to also use &lt;a href=&#34;https://duckduckgo.com/&#34;&gt;DuckDuckGo&lt;/a&gt; rather than Google Search, and consider &lt;a href=&#34;https://natehn.com/posts/leaving-facebook/&#34;&gt;leaving corporate social media&lt;/a&gt; altogether. (I&amp;rsquo;m partway through my own journey, but there is still work (especially de-Google-ing) to be done.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Because of advanced &lt;a href=&#34;https://coveryourtracks.eff.org/learn&#34;&gt;fingerprinting&lt;/a&gt; techniques, there&amp;rsquo;s no real perfect system for avoiding trackers. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.torproject.org/&#34;&gt;Tor&lt;/a&gt; might be your best option if a stronger form of anonymity is required.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Here are a few resources I use to choose my apps and tools, for both secure and open source alternatives:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.privacytools.io/&#34;&gt;PrivacyTools.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://prism-break.org/en/&#34;&gt;Prism Break&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://alternativeto.net/&#34;&gt;AlternativeTo.net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://switching.software/&#34;&gt;switching.software&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/awesome-social-distancing/blob/master/README.md&#34;&gt;Awesome Social Distancing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://list.romainaubert.com/&#34;&gt;Romain Aubert&amp;rsquo;s list of great tools&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://romainaubert.com/privacy-alternatives-to-google&#34;&gt;Google Alternatives&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ssd.eff.org/en/module-categories/tool-guides&#34;&gt;EFF&amp;rsquo;s Tool Guides&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;10&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When thinking about companies/apps themselves, the ideal of privacy is inverted - instead of privacy, we seek transparency. That&amp;rsquo;s why going with open-source, decentralized,  and/or audited tools is recommended where possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Decentralization distributes power. Consequently, trust is distributed among multiple parties, allowing for less of a dependence on a central node but a larger number of potential fail points.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One of the challenges in talking about digital security broadly and to a variety of different people is that there are many different potential threats, and they do not affect all of us equally. The digital world is not always safe for &lt;a href=&#34;https://loomio-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com/documents/files/000/209/867/original/nypdzine.pdf&#34;&gt;overpoliced&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.getrevue.co/profile/themarkup/issues/the-rise-and-the-recurring-bias-of-risk-assessment-algorithms-418128&#34;&gt;Black&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/inequality/2017/aug/08/rise-of-the-racist-robots-how-ai-is-learning-all-our-worst-impulses&#34;&gt;folks&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.takebackthetech.net/know-more/extortion&#34;&gt;non&lt;/a&gt;-&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.takebackthetech.net/know-more/cyberstalking&#34;&gt;cis&lt;/a&gt;-&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cnet.com/news/cameras-surveillance-and-the-sinister-tech-behind-domestic-abuse/&#34;&gt;men&lt;/a&gt;, and sometimes makes stuff like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eff.org/wp/digital-privacy-us-border-2017&#34;&gt;racism&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://onlinesafety.feministfrequency.com/en/&#34;&gt;sexism&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://hackblossom.org/domestic-violence/&#34;&gt;domestic violence&lt;/a&gt; even worse. White men like me need to remember that we do not face the same challenges as &lt;a href=&#34;https://hackblossom.org/cybersecurity/&#34;&gt;others&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At the same time, the truth is that everyone has &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.privacytools.io/#sponsors&#34;&gt;something to hide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Saying that you don&amp;rsquo;t need or want privacy because you have nothing to hide is to assume that no one should have, or could have, to hide anything - including their immigration status, unemployment history, financial history, and health records. You&amp;rsquo;re assuming that no one, including yourself, might object to revealing to anyone information about their religious beliefs, political affiliations, and sexual activities, as casually as some choose to reveal their movie and music tastes and reading preferences.&amp;rdquo; - Edward Snowden&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;14&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Security is protection against threats. One way to talk about digital security is via the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.forcepoint.com/cyber-edu/cia-triad&#34;&gt;CIA triad&lt;/a&gt;: confidentiality (who has access, a.k.a. privacy), integrity (protecting data), and availability (the system still works for authorized users).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In most cases you &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pcworld.com/article/3434097/why-you-can-stop-paying-for-antivirus-software.html&#34;&gt;probably don&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/wirecutter/blog/best-antivirus/&#34;&gt;need to&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://linuxhint.com/why_no_antivirus_linux/&#34;&gt;buy any&lt;/a&gt; anti-virus software. Just set up your system to be as safe as possible using the tools it provides.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://natehn.com/abstract-projection-2.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;Another abstract projection in my kitchen.&#34;/&gt; &lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Another abstract projection in my kitchen.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;ol start=&#34;16&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is a lot for you to do, however, to keep yourself secure online. Firstly, use a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.privacytools.io/software/passwords/&#34;&gt;password manager&lt;/a&gt; and enable two-factor authentication on your accounts. Make sure to vary both your usernames and passwords (if you need to remember a particular password, try &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.useapassphrase.com/&#34;&gt;using a passphrase&lt;/a&gt;. You can even draw the passphrase words out of a hat or something. You should also add &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eff.org/https-everywhere&#34;&gt;HTTPS Everywhere&lt;/a&gt; to your browser to ensure your browsing activity is encrypted through HTTPS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mathematically scrambling data - encryption - is one of the most powerful tools we have for maintaining digital security. &lt;a href=&#34;https://ssd.eff.org/en/module/deep-dive-end-end-encryption-how-do-public-key-encryption-systems-work&#34;&gt;End-to-end (E2E) encrypted&lt;/a&gt; apps like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.signal.org/&#34;&gt;Signal&lt;/a&gt; are particularly important and useful. Most people don&amp;rsquo;t realize that they use encryption every day through &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTTPS&#34;&gt;HTTPS&lt;/a&gt; and core Internet protocols like TLS and S/MIME.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure to &lt;a href=&#34;https://spreadprivacy.com/how-to-encrypt-devices/&#34;&gt;encrypt your computer(s) and phone(s)&lt;/a&gt; as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.privacytools.io/providers/vpn/&#34;&gt;Using a VPN is not enough&lt;/a&gt; if you want to keep your activities secure and private - try &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.torproject.org/&#34;&gt;Tor&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.signal.org/&#34;&gt;Signal&lt;/a&gt; instead (or in addition to a vetted VPN like &lt;a href=&#34;https://protonvpn.com/&#34;&gt;ProtonVPN&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You must also stay vigilant. Sophisticated &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/phishing&#34;&gt;phishing&lt;/a&gt; attacks are something that you - and anyone known to be associated with you - will need to be careful of. These aren&amp;rsquo;t your average spam messages. These are often meant specifically for you, replicating emails and websites that you might use in order to try to get your passwords or personal information. It could look like an email with a link from your bank, email, or social media account, for example - and the link will send you to a site run by the hacker(s). To defend yourself, first &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/u9dBGWVwMMA?t=60&#34;&gt;educate yourself on phishing techniques&lt;/a&gt;. Then turn on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.csoonline.com/article/3239144/2fa-explained-how-to-enable-it-and-how-it-works.html&#34;&gt;two-factor authentication&lt;/a&gt; for all of your accounts, preferably either through an &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/wirecutter/reviews/best-two-factor-authentication-app/&#34;&gt;authenticator app&lt;/a&gt; or even a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/wirecutter/reviews/best-security-keys/&#34;&gt;physical security key&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;In a world where millions of digital communications are silently intercepted, collected, and stored every day, how do activists effectively say &amp;lsquo;I do not consent to this search?&amp;rsquo; As in a physical encounter with law enforcement, we must be proactive. Online, this means using encryption along with other privacy-protecting and autonomy-preserving tools.&amp;rdquo; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://cldc.org/&#34;&gt;Civil Liberties Defense Center&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;21&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Going to a protest? See the &lt;a href=&#34;https://natehn.com/posts/iphone-security/&#34;&gt;iPhone Security Guide&lt;/a&gt; I put together a few days ago.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;notes-for-organizers-and-activists&#34;&gt;Notes for organizers and activists&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;22&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Organizers who seek to change the world face unique challenges that other folks do not need to deal with. Recent examples, like the &lt;a href=&#34;https://hongkongfp.com/2020/09/18/anonymous-site-ramps-up-doxxing-campaign-against-hong-kong-activists/&#34;&gt;doxing of pro-democracy activists&lt;/a&gt; in Hong Kong and revelations of &lt;a href=&#34;https://theintercept.com/2020/10/10/new-documents-reveal-how-the-animal-agriculture-industry-surveils-and-punishes-critics/&#34;&gt;private surveillance of animal rights groups and activists&lt;/a&gt;, not to mention movies like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.imdb.com/title/tt9784798/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Judas and the Black Messiah&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, are reminders of the importance of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.are.na/librarians-on-are-na/opsec-for-activists&#34;&gt;OPSEC for activists&lt;/a&gt; when dealing with &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Persona-based-training-matrix#the-matrix&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;assholes with resources&amp;rdquo; or even governmental entities&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Organizers are not only responsible for their personal security, but the security of their team and their activities. They also face greater risk and exposure due to their prominence within the group.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When it comes to setting standards for a small group or even an entire organization, we have to talk about &lt;strong&gt;security culture&lt;/strong&gt;. This goes way beyond choosing the &amp;ldquo;right&amp;rdquo; tools like &lt;a href=&#34;https://meet.jit.si/&#34;&gt;Jitsi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://signal.org/&#34;&gt;Signal&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.etesync.com/&#34;&gt;EteSync&lt;/a&gt; (etc).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Security culture&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Regardless of your personal risk level, defaulting to tools that are private and/or secure is the easiest way to maintain a culture that keeps its people safe from online surveillance. The focus on culture, rather than just implementing policy or focusing on individual actions, is something that - funnily enough - I have only run into in two places: the corporate world and the activist world.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;At a company like AT&amp;amp;T, security culture is focused on employees shared attitudes and actions related to corporate security policy and the way that affects their overall success. In their own words, security culture requires an &amp;ldquo;investment&amp;rdquo; of time and energy.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;For organizers, security culture is “&lt;a href=&#34;https://crimethinc.com/2004/11/01/what-is-security-culture&#34;&gt;a set of customs shared by a community whose members may be targeted, designed to minimize risk&lt;/a&gt;.” You should use secure practices from the beginning so that you don’t have to come up with security measures over and over again. It&amp;rsquo;s a form of collective care as well - a defense against racist tech, doxing, and the far-right. Limiting the amount people know to only what they &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; to know can also help address issues like &lt;a href=&#34;http://undercoverresearch.net/1260-2/&#34;&gt;undercover surveillance&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twincitiesgdc.org/badjacketing/&#34;&gt;badjacketing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;For both organizers and corporations, the focus is on culture, not protocol. The focus is on habits, not rules. They use different terms, but the core is the same: security culture is about making security the default - for everything. Security culture is a framework to center when working with others in an activist space. The best way to keep each other safe is to engage in secure practices at all times, not just by using particular tools, but by creating a culture of security.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;25&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One concern for organizers (along with journalists and politicians) is &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Doxing&#34;&gt;doxing&lt;/a&gt;. One preventative steps is to remove as much of your information from data brokers as possible. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.propublica.org/article/privacy-tools-opting-out-from-data-brokers&#34;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://open.nytimes.com/how-to-dox-yourself-on-the-internet-d2892b4c5954&#34;&gt;are&lt;/a&gt; a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.crashoverridenetwork.com/preventingdoxing.html&#34;&gt;few&lt;/a&gt; useful guides. If you are doxed, see &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@EqualityLabs/anti-doxing-guide-for-activists-facing-attacks-from-the-alt-right-ec6c290f543c&#34;&gt;Equality Labs&amp;rsquo; guide&lt;/a&gt; for next steps, and seek out help. Cyber Civil Rights Initiative also has an &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cybercivilrights.org/online-removal/&#34;&gt;online removal guide&lt;/a&gt;. Another potential layer of protection is to use a post office box or service like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.virtualpostmail.com/&#34;&gt;VirtualPostMail&lt;/a&gt; so that you don&amp;rsquo;t have to include your residential address on public documents. (If you own your property, however, there may be no way to avoid it.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One of the most useful tools for organizers is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.torproject.org/&#34;&gt;Tor&lt;/a&gt;. Tor harnesses decentralization and encryption to create anonymity. But make sure to sign into accounts you set up on Tor &lt;em&gt;on Tor&lt;/em&gt; - never deanonymize yourself by logging in to an anonymous account through a regular browser. (&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/J1q4Ir2J8P8?t=698&#34;&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t F it up!&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Another useful tool built upon Tor is &lt;a href=&#34;https://onionshare.org/&#34;&gt;OnionShare&lt;/a&gt;, developed by &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/micahflee&#34;&gt;Micah Lee&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;em&gt;The Intercept&lt;/em&gt;, which can be used to share files and host .onion hidden services. Micah recently wrote up &lt;a href=&#34;https://micahflee.com/2021/02/onionshare-anonymous-dropbox-raspberry-pi/&#34;&gt;instructions&lt;/a&gt; for how to set up an anonymous dropbox on a Raspberry Pi.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many people who use Signal all the time do not take advantage of all of its security features. Make sure to &lt;a href=&#34;https://support.signal.org/hc/en-us/articles/360007060632-What-is-a-safety-number-and-why-do-I-see-that-it-changed-&#34;&gt;compare safety numbers&lt;/a&gt; with people you are in contact with to avoid man-in-the-middle attacks and other vulnerabilities - preferably in an audible manner, on video chat, or in some non-Signal, offline way.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To give out your Signal number without publicizing your personal number, see &lt;em&gt;The Intercept&lt;/em&gt;&amp;lsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://theintercept.com/2017/09/28/signal-tutorial-second-phone-number/&#34;&gt;guide to using a different phone number&lt;/a&gt; on Signal. Make sure to also &lt;a href=&#34;https://theintercept.com/2020/09/25/surveillance-sim-cloning-protests-protect-phone/&#34;&gt;add a carrier pin to your phone(s)&lt;/a&gt;. And if you are prominent organizer, having &lt;a href=&#34;https://theintercept.com/2020/06/15/protest-tech-safety-burner-phone/&#34;&gt;burner&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.filippo.io/securing-a-travel-iphone/&#34;&gt;phones&lt;/a&gt; is probably not a bad idea. Services like &lt;a href=&#34;https://mysudo.com/&#34;&gt;MySudo&lt;/a&gt; can be an option, but they will be tied to your payment method. (My &lt;a href=&#34;https://natehn.com/posts/iphone-security/&#34;&gt;protester iPhone guide&lt;/a&gt; is probably also relevant.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A tool built upon Signal that will be useful to many organizers is &lt;a href=&#34;https://signalboost.info/&#34;&gt;Signalboost&lt;/a&gt;. Check it out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you need a &amp;ldquo;burner&amp;rdquo; email address, your best option is probably &lt;a href=&#34;https://protonmail.com/&#34;&gt;ProtonMail&lt;/a&gt;, since they don&amp;rsquo;t require you to connect an existing email address or phone number. Make sure to set it up through Tor and only access it through Tor. Be careful when &lt;a href=&#34;https://protonmail.com/support/knowledge-base/what-is-encrypted/&#34;&gt;using ProtonMail&lt;/a&gt; - just using the service is not enough to fully secure your communications with PGP encryption. If you just need a disposable address, try &lt;a href=&#34;https://maildrop.cc/&#34;&gt;Maildrop&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://33mail.com/&#34;&gt;33mail&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PGP (a.k.a. GPG) is an important and widely-used encryption tool. But its &lt;a href=&#34;https://secushare.org/PGP&#34;&gt;issues&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://latacora.micro.blog/2019/07/16/the-pgp-problem.html&#34;&gt;are&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/crypto/comments/cgty98/alternatives_to_pgp/&#34;&gt;well&lt;/a&gt;-&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.gtank.cc/modern-alternatives-to-pgp/&#34;&gt;documented&lt;/a&gt;. Make sure you &lt;a href=&#34;https://riseup.net/en/security/message-security&#34;&gt;read up&lt;/a&gt; before using it, and remember, only the body of the message is encrypted. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mailvelope.com/en/&#34;&gt;Mailvelope&lt;/a&gt; is the most user-friendly PGP client I&amp;rsquo;ve encountered. But skipping PGP and just using Signal is probably your best option.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When using Firefox, consider using an enhanced privacy configuration like &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/arkenfox/user.js&#34;&gt;the arkenfox user.js&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And even after all this, there are also physical-world threats that intersect with digital security. Some relevant tools include &lt;a href=&#34;https://guardianproject.github.io/haven/&#34;&gt;Haven&lt;/a&gt; and RF-shielded (a.k.a. Faraday) bags. There are also &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.privacytools.io/operating-systems/&#34;&gt;alternative operating systems&lt;/a&gt; appropriate for high-level security.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://natehn.com/abstract-projection-3.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;A third abstract video projected onto my kitchen wall.&#34;/&gt; &lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;A third abstract video projected onto my kitchen wall.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the challenges with digital security is that it is constantly shifting and changing as new apps are created, new threats are discovered, and they way we engage with technology and the Internet continues to evolve. But seeking to learn how the technological systems we rely on actually work, and taking control of the ways we engage with them, is a political act.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is so much to say on this topic - I haven&amp;rsquo;t even scratched the surface. Here are a few more resources to dig into to learn more:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://riseup.net/en/security&#34;&gt;RiseUp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki&#34;&gt;AnarchoTechNYC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ssd.eff.org/&#34;&gt;Surveillance Self Defense&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ourdataourselves.tacticaltech.org/posts/the-organisers-activity-book/&#34;&gt;The Organiser&amp;rsquo;s Activity Book&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://securityinabox.org/en/&#34;&gt;Security in a Box&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If we want to see change in our lives, we have to change things ourselves.”  - Grace Lee Boggs&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Activist iPhone Security Guide</title>
      <link>https://natehn.com/posts/iphone-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://natehn.com/posts/iphone-security/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://natehn.com/phones.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;Three protesters hold their phones up above a crowd.&#34;/&gt; &lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Three protesters hold their phones up above a crowd.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you attend a protest, particularly one which which might garner the attention of the authorities, it&amp;rsquo;s a good practice to limit the amount of data being sent out by your phone as much as possible. To start, here are things you should have set up in your phone at all times:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Limit ad tracking:&lt;/strong&gt; open the &lt;code&gt;Settings&lt;/code&gt; app; &lt;code&gt;Privacy&lt;/code&gt;; scroll down to the bottom of the Privacy settings; &lt;code&gt;Advertising&lt;/code&gt;; toggle ON &lt;code&gt;Limit Ad Tracking&lt;/code&gt; (you can also hit &lt;code&gt;Reset Advertising Identifier&lt;/code&gt; every once in a while)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Block analytics tracking:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;Settings&lt;/code&gt; app; &lt;code&gt;Privacy&lt;/code&gt;; scroll down to the bottom of the Privacy settings; &lt;code&gt;Analytics &amp;amp; Improvements&lt;/code&gt;; toggle OFF &lt;code&gt;Share iPhone Analytics&lt;/code&gt;,&lt;code&gt;Improve Sire &amp;amp; Dictation&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;Share iCloud Analytics&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Block location-based analytics:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;Settings&lt;/code&gt; app; &lt;code&gt;Privacy&lt;/code&gt;; &lt;code&gt;Location Services&lt;/code&gt;; &lt;code&gt;System Services&lt;/code&gt;; toggle OFF &lt;code&gt;iPhone Analytics&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Popular Near Me&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;Routing &amp;amp; Traffic&lt;/code&gt; (also feel free to toggle OFF as many of the things in this list and the &lt;code&gt;Location Services&lt;/code&gt; app list as you feel comfortable with)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Change your iPhone name&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code&gt;Settings&lt;/code&gt; app; &lt;code&gt;General&lt;/code&gt;; &lt;code&gt;About&lt;/code&gt;; &lt;code&gt;Name&lt;/code&gt;; change to something that provides no identifying information (including names, iPhone model, phone number, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use a strong passcode:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;Settings&lt;/code&gt; app; &lt;code&gt;Touch ID &amp;amp; Passcode&lt;/code&gt;; &lt;code&gt;Change Passcode&lt;/code&gt; (I recommend &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.useapassphrase.com/&#34;&gt;using a strong passphrase&lt;/a&gt; as your passcode to ensure that it is memorable but resistant to brute force attacks. You passcode should be alphanumeric at &lt;em&gt;least&lt;/em&gt; 10 digits long)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Turn off Siri:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;Settings&lt;/code&gt; app; &lt;code&gt;Siri &amp;amp; Search&lt;/code&gt;; toggle OFF all options&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Turn off dictation:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;Settings&lt;/code&gt; app; &lt;code&gt;General&lt;/code&gt;; &lt;code&gt;Keyboards&lt;/code&gt;; toggle OFF &lt;code&gt;Enable Dictation&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Turn off background app refresh for most apps:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;Settings&lt;/code&gt; app; &lt;code&gt;General&lt;/code&gt;; &lt;code&gt;Background App Refresh&lt;/code&gt;; toggle OFF all apps that are not secure/necessary&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Turn off Game Center&amp;rsquo;s location access:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;Settings&lt;/code&gt; app; &lt;code&gt;Game Center&lt;/code&gt;; toggle OFF &lt;code&gt;Game Center&lt;/code&gt;, or at least toggle OFF &lt;code&gt;Nearby Players&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Audit your apps&amp;rsquo; access:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;Settings&lt;/code&gt; app; &lt;code&gt;Privacy&lt;/code&gt;; check through this list and ensure that apps have no more access to your data than they need&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Harden  the default Safari browser:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;Settings&lt;/code&gt; app; &lt;code&gt;Safari&lt;/code&gt;; set &lt;code&gt;Search Engine&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;DuckDuckGo&lt;/code&gt;, toggle OFF &lt;code&gt;Search Engine Suggestions&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Safari Suggestions&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Preload Top Hit&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;Frequently Visited Sites&lt;/code&gt;; toggle ON &lt;code&gt;Block Pop-ups&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Prevent Cross-Site Tracking&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Block All Cookies&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;Fraudulent Website Warning&lt;/code&gt;; toggle OFF &lt;code&gt;Camera &amp;amp; Microphone Access&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Check for Apple Pay&lt;/code&gt;; select &lt;code&gt;Advanced&lt;/code&gt;; toggle OFF &lt;code&gt;Javascript&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should also keep your phone updated at all times (check in the &lt;code&gt;Settings&lt;/code&gt; app; &lt;code&gt;General&lt;/code&gt;; &lt;code&gt;Software Update&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before you head out to a protest, do the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Back up your phone:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;Settings&lt;/code&gt; app; your name at the top; &lt;code&gt;iCloud&lt;/code&gt;; &lt;code&gt;iCloud Backup&lt;/code&gt;; toggle it ON if not on already; select &lt;code&gt;Back Up Now&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Turn on Low Power Mode:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;Settings&lt;/code&gt; app; &lt;code&gt;Battery&lt;/code&gt;; toggle ON &lt;code&gt;Low Power Mode&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Turn off Touch ID and access to phone functions while locked:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;Settings&lt;/code&gt; app; &lt;code&gt;Touch ID &amp;amp; Passcode&lt;/code&gt;; type passcode; toggle &lt;code&gt;iPhone Unlock&lt;/code&gt; to OFF (you can be coerced into putting your thumb on your phone); set &lt;code&gt;Require Passcode&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;Immediately&lt;/code&gt;; toggle &lt;code&gt;Voice Dial&lt;/code&gt; OFF; toggle all options under &lt;code&gt;Allow access while locked&lt;/code&gt; to OFF; at the bottom, toggle ON wiping your phone after 10 failed attempts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Set a quicker auto-lock:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;Settings&lt;/code&gt; app; &lt;code&gt;Display &amp;amp; Brightness&lt;/code&gt;; &lt;code&gt;Auto-Lock&lt;/code&gt;; &lt;code&gt;30 seconds&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Turn off methods for connecting to your device:&lt;/strong&gt; open the &lt;code&gt;Settings&lt;/code&gt; app; &lt;code&gt;General&lt;/code&gt;; set &lt;code&gt;Airdrop&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;Receiving off&lt;/code&gt;; set &lt;code&gt;Handoff&lt;/code&gt; to OFF&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Turn off Wi-Fi&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code&gt;Settings&lt;/code&gt; app; &lt;code&gt;Wi-Fi&lt;/code&gt;; toggle OFF&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Turn off your GPS:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;Settings&lt;/code&gt; app; &lt;code&gt;Privacy&lt;/code&gt;; &lt;code&gt;Location Services&lt;/code&gt;; toggle OFF at the top - if you cannot to this, then at least turn it off for most apps and toggle OFF &lt;code&gt;Share My Location&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Turn off fitness tracking:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;Settings&lt;/code&gt; app; &lt;code&gt;Privacy&lt;/code&gt;; &lt;code&gt;Motion &amp;amp; Fitness&lt;/code&gt;; toggle OFF &lt;code&gt;Fitness Tracking&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Turn off Bluetooth:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;Settings&lt;/code&gt; app; &lt;code&gt;Bluetooth&lt;/code&gt;; set to OFF (unless you need it for what you are doing)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Turn off notification previews&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code&gt;Settings&lt;/code&gt; app; &lt;code&gt;Notifications&lt;/code&gt;; &lt;code&gt;Show Previews&lt;/code&gt;; select &lt;code&gt;Never&lt;/code&gt;; then go through each app in the list and toggle OFF &lt;code&gt;Show on Lock Screen&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Turn off automatic (non-encrypted) SMS messages:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;Settings&lt;/code&gt; app; &lt;code&gt;Messages&lt;/code&gt;; toggle &lt;code&gt;Send as SMS&lt;/code&gt; OFF (&lt;em&gt;note&lt;/em&gt;: this doesn&amp;rsquo;t completely turn off SMS, so you&amp;rsquo;ll still need to use &lt;a href=&#34;https://signal.org/&#34;&gt;Signal&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep in mind that turning off your phone is an option, as is turning it to airplane mode, or even leaving it at home - but communication is key when you are out on the streets, so I don&amp;rsquo;t recommend it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While you are out and about, use &lt;a href=&#34;https://signal.org/&#34;&gt;Signal&lt;/a&gt; for your communications and &lt;a href=&#34;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/firefox-focus-privacy-browser/id1055677337&#34;&gt;Firefox Focus&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/brave-private-web-browser-vpn/id1052879175&#34;&gt;Brave&lt;/a&gt; for browsing. Another good idea is to download maps onto your phone ahead of time so that you don&amp;rsquo;t need to use location services on your GPS/maps app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When livestreaming, avoid showing fellow protesters&amp;rsquo; faces, particularly if they are doing something that would garner the authorities&amp;rsquo; attention. If you post videos or photos afterward, make sure to blur out faces and potentially identifying details of fellow activists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Missing something? &lt;a href=&#34;https://natehn.com/connect/&#34;&gt;Let me know&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ll be following up soon with &lt;a href=&#34;https://natehn.com/posts/digital-security/&#34;&gt;an article on digital security more generally&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflecting on 2020</title>
      <link>https://natehn.com/posts/2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://natehn.com/posts/2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;[Feel free to listen to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mixcloud.com/nthnh/jan-2021-mix-w-nathan-hewitt-3/&#34;&gt;my most recent mix&lt;/a&gt; while reading if you want some background music.]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the beginning and end of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://decolonialatlas.wordpress.com/2020/12/31/new-years-around-the-world-2021/&#34;&gt;Western&lt;/a&gt; calendar year are quite arbitrary, they have become integral to the way that our society thinks about time. For most of 2020, we were complaining about, well, &lt;em&gt;2020&lt;/em&gt;. Beginning with fears of WWIII and wildfires, then a global pandemic and US presidential election, the past year has thrown a lot at us. Somehow, however, there was an inkling of irrational hope that a new year would bring us a better world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now we&amp;rsquo;re in 2021, and &amp;ldquo;2020&amp;rdquo; just keeps coming. Obviously, the pandemic is far from over. And politics in America, spurred on by &lt;a href=&#34;https://natehn.com/posts/leaving-facebook/#fn:11&#34;&gt;social media&lt;/a&gt; radicalization, continues to deteriorate. Still, I thought it might be useful - to some degree for people in the present, and perhaps also for folks in the future - to reflect on the past calendar year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://natehn.com/mask.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;A disposable mask with a broken ear string.&#34;/&gt; &lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;A disposable mask with a broken ear string.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-world-through-a-screen&#34;&gt;The world, through a screen&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do you even write about something like COVID - something that affects everyone?  Whatever your experience has been, it cannot come anywhere close to capturing the full experience of humanity during this time. The experiences are so different, of course on an individual basis, but also along class and racial lines. I&amp;rsquo;m still employed full-time, while former coworkers and neighbors and friends are without work. I&amp;rsquo;ve not lost anyone I know to the disease, and yet thousands of people have died.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As different as all of our lives are, one shared experience for people in the US is an increased reliance on technology. In a recent newsletter, Tech Learning Collective wrote that, &amp;ldquo;2020 was, without a doubt, &lt;strong&gt;the most Cyberpunk-dystopic year in recorded history&lt;/strong&gt;.&amp;rdquo; They continue:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was the year of Zoom dinner parties, pandemic-fueled bot-powered Instacart panic-buying, and direct-to-streaming Hollywood releases. The Pirate Bay has never had high-quality TV and movie rips indexed so quickly. Installing a bot to snag grocery delivery slots has never been a mode of survival before. This was the year even the tech-averse were forced into cyberspace for virtual concerts, remote learning, an augmented-reality holiday parade, and contactless-everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technology, already an enormous part of modern life, has become our way of engaging with everything during quarantine. And for a brief moment, when the pandemic first arrived in the US, it felt like we were united against something for once - the disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://natehn.com/tea.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;Some tea packets and tags.&#34;/&gt; &lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Some tea packets and tags.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That feeling did not last for long. After all, with 24/7 news cycles and social media, we experience life very differently from one another and from humans in times past. Now, far-away events can affect our emotions more than activities close to home. Political affiliation defines our identity; the global is personal. And as Internet use increased during lockdown, our slowly diverging realities pulled apart even further and at a greater rate.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this year, I came to realize the degree to which we no longer have a shared reality. I&amp;rsquo;m not just talking about politics. We see different memes and content; we hear about different celebrities; we see different kinds of social media posts; we read different blogs. Sure, we&amp;rsquo;ve all always had our own lives and experiences. What is different is that, for many people, their reality is now organized for the profit of Silicon Valley venture capitalists and NYSE investors who profit from algorithmically cultivating these realities - competing visions for how the world actually works.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first, when the pandemic hit, I dove into Facebook, seeking socialization. I was particularly active after the killing of George Floyd in late May. But over time, as the intensity of these diverging realities started to grow - and my attempts to connect with other people saw little assistance from the algorithms - I realized that there wasn&amp;rsquo;t much for me to accomplish on the platform itself. Rather than socialization and connection, my social media experience was one of visceral and vicarious chaos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://natehn.com/banjo1.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;Some banjo picks.&#34;/&gt; &lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Some banjo picks.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I shifted my attention toward the ways I, myself, was interacting with technology. Although I have always used the computer a lot, I was now at a desk more than ever before. I started to reconsider the way I approach the Internet&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and took on a number of related projects:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Building this low-energy, self-hosted website.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attempting to solar-power it - but I didn&amp;rsquo;t quite get the right equipment, and our apartment doesn&amp;rsquo;t get enough sunlight anyway. I learned a lot, but eventually decided to give up for now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stopping using Facebook and Instagram - I hadn&amp;rsquo;t decided to leave yet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Going through the many linked articles and content I had collected over the years. Some of it I threw away, and the rest I rearranged so that it would be more useful for me. (This is a work in progress. More on this in a future post.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cleaning out my Google Drive, moving a bunch of old stuff to offline storage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deciding to re-start my personal newsletter, this time having folks to opt in rather than importing an email list.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learning a bunch from Tech Learning Collective about technology and security.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:5&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Starting to think a lot more about the ways that I keep in touch with people. Who facilitates my communications? Do I trust them with my personal information?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Committing to &lt;a href=&#34;https://natehn.com/posts/leaving-facebook/&#34;&gt;leaving Facebook and Instagram&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I continue to engage with technology, using more open source tools, relying less on big business and more on myself and online communities, I hope I can also inspire others to do the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technology is not going anywhere, and it is amazing how little most of us know about how the Internet, for instance, actually works. Not everyone needs to be a developer, but I believe that if we all had a better understanding of the apps and programs we use, we would be a lot better at fixing the broken systems we&amp;rsquo;re contending with right now. As we move into 2021, I&amp;rsquo;m feeling more confident, and more competent. I&amp;rsquo;m no code whiz, but I know my way around a bit better. I plan to continue to learn and grow in the new year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;making-music-in-the-middle-of-all-this&#34;&gt;Making music in the middle of all this&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the tensions at the heart of my musicmaking practice has been the push and pull of professional and personal. My background in music in the classical world always emphasized the professional aspects of sound, but during college, studying free improvisation with Rui Li was an entry point into more intimate ways of engaging with my instruments. Since I graduated music school and started making electronic music, that push and pull has remained.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;music-for-fifteen-emails&#34;&gt;Music for Fifteen Emails&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the pandemic first shut things down in mid-March, I threw myself into the professional side of my work. I had been listening to a great deal of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.factmag.com/2018/01/14/japanese-ambient-hiroshi-yoshimora-midori-takada/&#34;&gt;environmental music&lt;/a&gt;, especially the work of Hiroshi Yoshimura. I had also been recording a lot with one of the instruments Hiroshi used, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://natehn.com/posts/music-studio-nov-2020/&#34;&gt;Yamaha FB-01&lt;/a&gt;. Without really thinking about it too much, I instinctively seized on the opportunity to work on something I had wanted to work on for a while: a new album.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My connection with environmental music only increased as it soothed me during a time of extreme change. I put in several hours per day after work, racing through it because I really felt it was the right music for the right time. (I have heard from friends that I was right - it did fit the time. And depending on how your life is now, &lt;a href=&#34;https://nthnh.bandcamp.com/album/music-for-fifteen-emails-part-one&#34;&gt;it still might be&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://nthnh.bandcamp.com/album/music-for-fifteen-emails-part-one&#34;&gt;[Listen to Part One]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With &lt;em&gt;Music for Fifteen Emails&lt;/em&gt;, I chose to experiment in a lot of different ways - I had not done anything like it before, in terms of genre, in terms of making music on a grid (sort-of) in terms of getting serious about mixing, and mastering myself (paying monthly for a mastering suite via Splice) rather than paying someone else. The album burgeoned into a double-album and I released it in April, after about a month of quarantine-fueled labor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided that this time I would spend more time exploring promotion and distribution. I switched from Distrokid to CDBaby since CDBaby is a single payment and allows multiple artists. I also used SubmitHub to try and bring attention to my music - a first for me. It resulted in a few playlistings and blog reviews - more attention than my releases usually get - but not as much as I had hoped. I also used my personal Instagram more than I ever had before, and even paid for an ad on that platform for the first time (this is before I decided to leave Instagram).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://nthnh.bandcamp.com/album/music-for-fifteen-emails-part-two&#34;&gt;[Listen to Part Two]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know if the promotional work can be characterized as a success, but it was a useful experiment. The feedback that brings me the most joy is that of my friends who have enjoyed it the most and shared with me how they continue to listen to it to this day: A.M., J.W., L.V., and L.R.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;music-for-self-reflection&#34;&gt;Music for self-reflection&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recognize now that putting all of that time into the album was a coping mechanism. After I released and promoted &lt;em&gt;Music for Fifteen Emails&lt;/em&gt;, for a while, I didn&amp;rsquo;t work on music very much, and I started to get swept away by the news cycle and social media. After all, with the complete collapse of the performing arts, there weren&amp;rsquo;t really any opportunities to perform live, and I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure that I really felt like it anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, I continued to make music just for myself - the personal side of my music practice. At one point in late spring, my partner and I ran across a snail moving alongside the sidewalk in the park. I decided to play a little song to go along with the video footage we collected:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/fJFOMbbDGCE&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a while in late spring, the social uprising and Black Lives Matter movement occupied my mind and time (well, it still does) to a degree that there was not space in my life for musicmaking. I also realized during that time that COVID was not ending anytime soon. The weight of that realization, combined with police brutality and the onset of the general election season in June/July, meant that I did not really &lt;em&gt;feel&lt;/em&gt; musical. Instead, I distracted myself with basketball, and with cooking, and with building a home routine with my partner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually, however, I started to feel the need to make music again. Music helps me to process the world around me, and the emotions within me, and my relationships and experiences. I was overwhelmed, but as I adapted to the situation we were in in fall 2020 - as humans do - I started to try and process those experiences. Sometimes, I just improvised on my keyboard - letting it all out. Other times, I tried to approach the instrument with more intention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://natehn.com/banjo2.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;More banjo picks.&#34;/&gt; &lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;More banjo picks.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the year went on, I moved farther and farther into quiet. My recordings were peppered with longer tones and deconstructed melodies. Improvisations, rather than compositions - perhaps because my ability to create order felt like it was slipping away in all of the chaos surrounding us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In September, I went on a walk to a nearby grocery store and pulled out my phone to record the trip. When I got back, I decided to record over it - &lt;a href=&#34;https://nthnh.bandcamp.com/track/in-the-middle-of-all-this&#34;&gt;a single long improvisation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is what I later wrote about the piece, entitled &lt;em&gt;In the Middle of All This&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Popular music, especially in the age of the Digital Audio Workstation, is constructed almost 1 millisecond at a time. Every note, every harmony, every effect is dissected and reconstructed over and over again until is is absolutely perfect. Live performances are often filtered and shaped to resemble that magical &amp;ldquo;take.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Middle of All This &lt;em&gt;is a piece that rejects the impulse to finish. It rejects, even, the impulse to edit (beyond matching levels and removing loud pops). It consists of two field recordings, digitally scotch-taped together to resemble just one (they were separated in reality by a 20 minute grocery run), with a later improvisation recorded over the field recording(s). It is a simple diorama - nothing sophisticated.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The improvisations take the form of deconstructed musical ideas, sometimes taking cues from the field recording, sometimes coming from within the performer himself (a white dude sitting in his apartment in West Harlem in the middle of a pandemic). If you played them on top of one another, they could almost make a song. But they don&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The world feels just a little bit like it is coming apart. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if &amp;ldquo;deconstructed&amp;rdquo; is the right word for the way I think about it - that feels somehow to purposeful. But as a musician, I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel like I would be reflecting the world I see by putting together a cohesive musical unit. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if I had the emotional strength to offer one either. The best I could do was these almost-but-not-quite-hopeful motives.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(I&amp;rsquo;m super excited for this piece to be included in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.artwithjip.com/&#34;&gt;Jip Gallery&lt;/a&gt;&amp;lsquo;s next exhibition.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A month later, I decided to sit down and record a drone EP, &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://nthnh.bandcamp.com/album/in-those-places-we-are-the-ghosts&#34;&gt;In those places, we are the ghosts.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d been wanting to make some drone for a while, but I never felt fully inspired to do so until October 2020. Perhaps it had to do with the darkness of the year, or the spooky Halloween vibes that felt so right, but I wanted to make something a bit grungier, a bit darker, and a bit more indulgent.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:6&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;music--tech&#34;&gt;Music + tech&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the last couple months of the year, I have entered into another period of technical experimentation. I&amp;rsquo;m playing with beatmaking, various livecoding languages, Max MSP, 3D spatial audio, and video synthesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you are put under stress, sometimes you find out what matters most to you. No matter what happens, or where my career takes me, or how much money I have, music will always be an important part of my life. It&amp;rsquo;s magic. Whether I am the listener, curator, or performer, active engagement with sound rarely fails to restore me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;quarantine-lifestyle-log&#34;&gt;Quarantine lifestyle log&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;spring&#34;&gt;Spring&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been super fortunate: no deaths in my immediate extended family, not fired/furloughed/laid off, no COVID - or at least no symptoms and no positive tests. The reality is, the biggest impacts on me, personally, were on my lifestyle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although I&amp;rsquo;ve always been partial to just staying at home on the weekends, there were always things that drew me out of the apartment. Whether it was the 50th-anniversary gala I was working on at the time, museum ethics organizing, or climate activism,&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:7&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; my life changed dramatically when the world ground to a halt - and I know I&amp;rsquo;m hardly unique in that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My work life, however, continued on, at least initially unchanged. I already worked from home on the Fractured Atlas team. Eventually, Fractured Atlas would be affected greatly by COVID, due to layoffs and the great challenges that our member artists faced, but at first, I felt lucky that we didn&amp;rsquo;t have to changing our protocols very much.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:8&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:8&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Early on, I began to engage in mutual aid where I could. I supported a few individuals directly and also started delivering groceries on a regular basis. As you may remember, the initial spike in NYC was intense, and groups like Invisible Hands mobilized to support at-risk folks in our communities. When we thought it was only going to last a short time, we also took on some classic stuck-at-home activities: puzzles and board games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One time, when my partner and I were sitting around in quarantine, maybe a month-and-a-half in, we decided to make a zine as a way off remembering that strange time. We gathered various items from our pandemic experience - Cheddar Sour Cream Ruffles bags, Chinese take-out sauce packets, banjo picks, and, of course, disposable masks, and arranged them on my flatbed scanner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://natehn.com/takeout.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;A bunch of unused Chinese takeout sauce packets.&#34;/&gt; &lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;A bunch of unused Chinese takeout sauce packets.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Naturally, that idea died away pretty quickly once we realized that the pandemic was not going to be over anytime soon. But that was my first realization that these times should be documented - the first, in a way, of many attempts to write about 2020. The scans from that evening are the images you see spread throughout this post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;summer&#34;&gt;Summer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While people on short-term leases and those with means left the city, we decided to stay. Eventually, my partner and I settled into a rhythm: working during the day, taking turns cooking&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:9&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:9&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and doing the dishes, daily walks, watching road cycling or maybe The Last Airbender, playing Overwatch, my partner playing banjo, weekly family chats, takeout once per week (occasionally cheating and picking up a pizza), and reading together in the evenings. We also started indoor composting, added some house plants, and did some virtual game nights. None of it particularly notable, except for how damn &lt;em&gt;reliable&lt;/em&gt; it was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/OT40Rmjwd-Q&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When George Floyd was killed, like many others, we sprung into action and marched the streets, probably two out of every three days. We decided to chance the subways and, other than delivering groceries, it was probably the most we were outside the entire year. Once the uprising started to die down, things for us, strangely, got back to &amp;ldquo;normal.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal, 08/19/2020, 1:36am&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have this nagging feeling that I am not doing something that I am supposed to be doing. But there isn&amp;rsquo;t anything. It&amp;rsquo;s strange. Hopefully, it&amp;rsquo;s just cabin fever. I guess I should just go to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;autumn&#34;&gt;Autumn&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking back at the year, the autumn is almost a blank spot in my memory. To some degree, every day was the same. I went to the Socrates Sculpture Park for a masked and socially-distanced hang with a couple of friends, and was blown away by the simple pleasure of it all. There were a couple short trips upstate, and one longer one to the Adirondacks that helped my partner and I to recharge. I started to look for a new job, and in the process joined the team part-time at &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/&#34;&gt;Open Collective&lt;/a&gt;. Eventually, at the end of the year, I left Fractured Atlas and joined &lt;a href=&#34;https://donorly.com/&#34;&gt;Donorly&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://natehn.com/ruffles.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;A scan of a Cheddar Sour Cream Ruffles bag.&#34;/&gt; &lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;A scan of a Cheddar Sour Cream Ruffles bag.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most difficult parts of the lockdown for us was being away from our families for so long. With both of us having at-risk people in our family bubbles, we had to proceed with extreme care. We eventually decided to take a six-week trip at the end of the year to see our folks in the Midwest - three weeks each - and due to our precautions no one got sick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The weird part about writing about pandemic life right now is that it hasn&amp;rsquo;t ended. We&amp;rsquo;re back in the city and have many of the same patterns. It seems like the vaccine will make 2021 a better year than 2020. But if this year has taught me anything, it&amp;rsquo;s to take nothing for granted. Come what may - after 2020, I&amp;rsquo;m ready for anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;feelings&#34;&gt;Feelings&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The year 2020 was filled with emotions. Anger at injustices like police brutality, government mishandling of COVID, fellow citizens&amp;rsquo; lack of care for the broader community, various politicians, and, you know, everything. Sadness for colleagues and friends whose lives were uprooted. Loneliness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I felt like I was floating through time - simultaneously untethered from reality and stuck in the same place. At other times, I was just bored. There were moments of fear as well, especially in the midst of great uncertainty. Fear of the future. Fear of death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there were also moments of great joy and brilliance. Though they were often overshadowed, those moments are the ones I cling to. I hope that you can do the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, to some degree people have always chosen news based on their viewpoint. But the niche-enabling dynamics of cable TV made being different profitable. On the Internet, it&amp;rsquo;s cable times a million. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: this is different from having conflicting opinions. We don&amp;rsquo;t even share the same basic facts about what &lt;em&gt;IS&lt;/em&gt; on a basic level vs what &lt;em&gt;IS NOT&lt;/em&gt;. Let alone what &lt;em&gt;ought&lt;/em&gt; to be. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the coolest groups I&amp;rsquo;ve started to follow in the tech world is &lt;a href=&#34;https://100r.co/site/home.html&#34;&gt;Hundred Rabbits&lt;/a&gt;. They traverse the world on their sailboat, making amazing tools like ORCA and Left and just generally inspire people to engage with technology differently. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A couple of years ago, I became impatient with social media, emailed a bunch of contacts, and accidentally broken some international data privacy laws in the process - whoops! I did a better job this time. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also taught a class on digital security basics for beginners in the audio production/journalism world. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:6&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mean, most people want a song with a beat that lasts no more than five minutes. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:7&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prior to the onset of the COVID-19 shutdown in New York, I was able to complete a few of my goals for the first half of 2020. For instance, in January, I created an &lt;a href=&#34;https://natehn.com/bibliography.pdf&#34;&gt;overview of critical external feedback&lt;/a&gt; for Extinction Rebellion, which was distributed to members of the NYC group. I also made my own trail mix for the first time. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:8&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of 2020, the team was cut almost in half. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:8&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of my goals for the first half of 2020 was to cook at least four new types of fish or meat substitutes. I accomplished that and much more, including my &lt;em&gt;pièce de résistance&lt;/em&gt;, a meatless edition of Scotch Eggs. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:9&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Studio (Nov. 2020)</title>
      <link>https://natehn.com/posts/music-studio-nov-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://natehn.com/posts/music-studio-nov-2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;My music studio (i.e., a little corner of our little office) is ever-changing. &lt;a href=&#34;http://martinyammoller.com/all-interviews/&#34;&gt;Instruments and gear&lt;/a&gt; come and go. Workflows ebb and&amp;hellip;flow. This is the first post in a &amp;ldquo;music studio&amp;rdquo; series where we check in on what tools I&amp;rsquo;m currently using for my audio work.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;gear&#34;&gt;Gear&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of the limited space in my NYC apartment, my music studio is relatively small, occupying just 1/3 of the space in the &amp;ldquo;office&amp;rdquo; of our 2BR living space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://natehn.com/studio.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;A photo of my music studio, described below.&#34;/&gt; &lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;A photo of my music studio, described below.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a list of the gear in the set-up shown above:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Elektron Digitakt drum computer/sampler&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DIY-built Monome Norns sound computer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yamaha FB-01 half-rack 4-operator FM synth module&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arturia Keystep midi keyboard/sequencer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Focusrite Saffire 4i4 (3rd gen) audio interface/sound card&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mackie 1202-VLZ3 12-channel analog mixer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a pair of JBL LSR305 powered monitors (speakers)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zoom H1n audio recorder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cheap Samson SR850 headphones&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Laptop, monitor, laptop stand, milk crate, powered USB hub, keyboard, mouse&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A bunch of audio cables&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the exception of the DIY Monome Norns, which I bought a kit for and assembled myself, and little things like the keyboard, mouse and USB hub, this equipment was bought used online. I&amp;rsquo;ve done a lot of buying and selling, going back to Spring 2017.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; The FB-01, although it has some noise issues, has been a real treat, and it is currently the only vintage gear in my workflow. The Norns adds some flexibility/mystery/inspiration to the setup, since it can serve many different purposes depending on what program it is running. The laptop is the core of the setup, and rest of the equipment is mostly functional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;routing&#34;&gt;Routing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;audio&#34;&gt;Audio&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The center hub of audio routing is the 12-channel mixer (1202). The best thing about this particular mixer - other than the fact that it fits inside the milk crate &lt;em&gt;perfectly&lt;/em&gt; - is its flexible routing features that allow me to route signals to multiple sources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To start, the external sources, in this case the Norns and FB-01, send audio into the mixer. I can play them without my laptop by sending their audio into the main outs of the mixer, which in turn sends audio out to the monitors/speakers and Zoom audio recorder. The 1202’s mute buttons also allow me to send thse external signals to an alternate bus that goes through the audio interface to my computer/DAW. This allows for a pseudo cue system, of sorts. I then have the outputs running from my computer, through the interface, back into the main mixer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, I can send audio out to the Norns (and other hardware effects I use from time to time) using the two FX sends on the mixer. Rather than using the mixer&amp;rsquo;s stereo returns, I prefer to use a regular input channel for each FX return, for maximum flexibility and control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;midi&#34;&gt;MIDI&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My main MIDI controller is the Keystep. I usually have it running via USB into my computer. I also connect it via a standard 5-pin MIDI cable to the Yamaha FB-01. Occasionally, I will connect it to the Norns via USB instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other important MIDI connection is the Sevilla host-to-host USB MIDI daptor, which allows me to send messages between the Norns (which is itself a computer/MIDI host) and my laptop. This is really useful for integrating the Norns into my setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Digitakt can also do some MIDI stuff, but I am not currently using it in that capacity. Something to explore later!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;computer-programs&#34;&gt;Computer Programs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My Windows laptop is at the heart of the setup. At the moment, I am still most comfortable using audio, MIDI, and virtual instruments/plugins in my DAW, Ableton Live 10, but I recently took a class on 3D immersive sound design using Unity and FMod. I&amp;rsquo;m quite intrigued and will probably look more into this over the coming months as an interesting delivery method/venue for my music. I have also been learning the very basics of Max 8 and a little bit of SuperCollider. We will see where all this leads!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve collected a lot of VSTs over the years, and it is not worth listing them all here. Instead, I&amp;rsquo;ll list some of the plugins and instruments I&amp;rsquo;ve been using the most lately:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Felt Instruments Lekko and Jasno&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a PureData emulation of the Lyra-8&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Valhalla plugins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arturia V Collection 7&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;various Airwindows plugins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Full Bucket Korg emulation VSTs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Amazing Noises Granular Mirror Maze&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sample-wise, I think I&amp;rsquo;m most excited about a big library of Elektron Machinedrum samples I recently downloaded. I&amp;rsquo;m also looking forward to exploring some vintage MFB drum samples as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;disclaimer&#34;&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am well aware of the limitations of buying music gear, and suspicious of the online culture of &amp;ldquo;G.A.S.&amp;rdquo; (gear aquisition syndrome) that is encouraged by music tech manufacturers.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; It can be tempting to think that a piece of gear is the only thing that you need to have the &amp;ldquo;perfect sound.&amp;rdquo; Besides the fact that there is no such thing as perfect, it is also important to remember that no piece of gear will make your music &amp;ldquo;better.&amp;rdquo; It can make music sound professionally produced&amp;hellip;but plenty of professionally-produced music is bad!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, &amp;ldquo;haptic feedback&amp;rdquo; - learning by touch/feel - can be a useful way to engage with music, especially when learning synthesis. There is nothing like turning the cutoff knob on an actual synthesizer. The physical exploration of the instrument can help you understand what is happening and allow for more natural exploration than what you experience on a computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After owning several analog synths and other hardware, I have come back around to primarily using software. This is partly because of a lack of space, but also it helps to save money - hardware is expensive!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From time to time, I run into folks who are purists about some sort of music format. Whether it is Eurorack, tabletop, vintage synths, pure DAW setups, rack gear, or whatever else they come up with, don&amp;rsquo;t follow a standard or format just &amp;ldquo;because.&amp;rdquo; Don&amp;rsquo;t think about how your desk is going to look. &lt;strong&gt;Follow the sound.&lt;/strong&gt; Focus on the results rather than aesthetics. And please don&amp;rsquo;t be afraid to have a laptop on stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;~&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to chat about music tech and gear, &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:nathan@omg.lol&#34;&gt;hit me up&lt;/a&gt;! I would love to talk about the highs and lows of building a productive music studio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More interested in the results? Check out my &lt;a href=&#34;https://nthnh.bandcamp.com/&#34;&gt;Bandcamp page&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At some point on this website I&amp;rsquo;ll have to reflect on some of my favorites that I had to let go, like the Behringer SH-101 clone and Korg MS-20 mini that I just simply do not have space for. The Behringer rack reverb I used to have was also great. These have been replaced by VSTs from folks like Valhalla and Full Bucket. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is for this reason that I do not link from this page to any stores or gear sites. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leaving Facebook</title>
      <link>https://natehn.com/posts/leaving-facebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://natehn.com/posts/leaving-facebook/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://natehn.com/fb1.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;A photo of me at a bowling alley.&#34;/&gt; &lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;A photo of me at a bowling alley.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why&#34;&gt;Why&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although there have been plenty of fun moments on the platform, and meaningful, valuable interactions, the truth is that I&amp;rsquo;ve spent most of my time scrolling, searching, looking for something that was never there. When I look back, my memory of Facebook is primarily connected with a deep social anxiety. The attention-grabbing notifications. The rollercoaster of self-worth. Every minute without a &amp;ldquo;like&amp;rdquo; was a failure. Every comment was a triumph. And even as I matured, those core feelings have never really left me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like many people, it took me a while to realize that the News Feed was not really a &amp;ldquo;public square.&amp;rdquo; My engagement with friends on the platform was governed by the whims of an algorithm that cared little for my health or the health of my relationships. Notifications did not signal authentic interactions, but rather served to keep me on the website. Every day, without my knowing it, the technology took advantage of my underlying psychology, using sophisticated, calculated tricks to hold my attention and show me more ads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://natehn.com/fb2.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;A photo of someone throwing water at me with a bucket.&#34;/&gt; &lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;A photo of someone throwing water at me with a bucket.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of you will be familiar with the saying that &amp;ldquo;If you aren&amp;rsquo;t paying for the product, you &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; the product.&amp;rdquo; In &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thesocialdilemma.com/&#34;&gt;The Social Dilemma&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; a documentary film about social media, Jaron Lanier puts a finer point on it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s the gradual, slight, imperceptible change in your own behavior and perception that is the product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who would I be if I had never joined Facebook? Would I be different? Definitely! But I don&amp;rsquo;t really know how, or in what way. So many of my deepest relationships have lived, at least in part, on a website whose goal is not to enrich my life, but rather to enrich itself. Every interaction I have had with friends and family on that platform is tainted by the fact that our connection was facilitated for the purpose of selling changes in our behavior to the highest bidder. For over a decade, almost all of my interpersonal communication was enabled and financed by persuasive technology and growth hacking. (This is surveillance capitalism, and it sucks.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://natehn.com/fb3.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;A group photo of me with five other people. Faces have been obscured.&#34;/&gt; &lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;A group photo of me with five other people. Faces have been obscured.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, leaving isn&amp;rsquo;t easy. Even though my use of Facebook has waned in various ways over the years, it still functions as a sort of rolodex, and as an archive of good times. When I first started thinking about leaving, a few thoughts kept pulling me back:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What if I want to talk to [person I haven&amp;rsquo;t spoken to in 10 years]?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How will I share about my life?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How will I look back at all those good memories and photos that are only on Facebook?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;basically: &amp;ldquo;What if I need it later?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook is a pathway to my past, with an (honestly) pretty good user interface, and it is hard to give up on that. This isn&amp;rsquo;t my first time trying to leave. But &lt;a href=&#34;https://psyche.co/guides/how-to-make-new-friends-when-youre-busy-with-adulthood&#34;&gt;making friends as an adult&lt;/a&gt; is hard enough as it is. I don&amp;rsquo;t need these companies to get involved in my social life by modifying my behavior - even modifying it by 0.01%. I&amp;rsquo;ll pass on leaving my self-esteem to the whims of their moneymaking algorithms. From here on, where I can, I want to engage as authentically as possible. I&amp;rsquo;m going to set my own boundaries. In so many ways, and for so many reasons, Facebook just isn&amp;rsquo;t cutting it. That&amp;rsquo;s it - I&amp;rsquo;m out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how&#34;&gt;How&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Facebook is so ingrained in my life, even after months of declining use, extricating it has been no easy task. I could quit the platform with no notice or preparation - cold turkey, like a couple of my closest friends - but I still feared losing touch with people who I only am connected with on Facebook, or losing track of the photos and memories that made me love it so much in the first place. As such, my goal is to replace all of the tools Facebook provides with my own, piece by piece.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://natehn.com/fb4.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;A photo of me with three other people. Inexplicably, I chose to face my chest away from the camera. Faces have been obscured.&#34;/&gt; &lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;A photo of me with three other people. Inexplicably, I chose to face my chest away from the camera. Faces have been obscured.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initially, when I was first thinking about the ways I engage with the platform, I ran into a post by my acquaintance (and Facebook friend) Sahar Massachi called &lt;a href=&#34;https://sahar.io/how-i-use-facebook/&#34;&gt;How I use Facebook&lt;/a&gt;. Since Sahar used to be an engineer on Facebook&amp;rsquo;s Civic team, I was intrigued and I followed a few of his suggestions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I told Facebook that I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to see ads anymore, over and over again, until I didn&amp;rsquo;t see as many ads&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I unliked all of my liked pages and only followed a few of them that were especially important to me&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I left most of my groups&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These changes were okay, but they didn&amp;rsquo;t release me from my core hang-ups with the platform. After another hour-long doom scroll on my phone, I deleted the mobile app. I had done this numerous times before, but it never stuck. I would be going to an event, or want to post a photo while out and about, and end up re-installing the app. Or I would just start opening up the mobile site in a browser.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the days of the pandemic, however, that was not a problem, and this time it worked. I&amp;rsquo;ve made it longer than ever before without using the mobile app, and I haven&amp;rsquo;t actually found that I need the platform at all. Now is my best chance to head off on my own - out into the unknown, a Facebook-less social world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;heres-how-ive-replaced-facebook&#34;&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s how I&amp;rsquo;ve replaced Facebook:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Facebook Feature&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;My Replacement&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Profile page&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://natehn.com/&#34;&gt;This website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Sharing updates and opinions&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Sending out a &lt;a href=&#34;https://buttondown.email/natehn&#34;&gt;quarterly newletter&lt;/a&gt; and posting on &lt;a href=&#34;https://natehn.com/posts/&#34;&gt;this blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Sharing memes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://natehn.com/posts/on-memes/&#34;&gt;Check it out&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Keeping up with the news&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Using an RSS reader&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; - just news, no comments section&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Database of people&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Making my own database on &lt;a href=&#34;https://airtable.com/&#34;&gt;Airtable&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:5&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Sharing artistic photos, sometimes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://vsco.co/natehnnn/gallery&#34;&gt;VSCO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;My personal photos&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:6&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; with friends and family&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;I originally moved these to &lt;a href=&#34;https://photos.google.com/&#34;&gt;Google Photos&lt;/a&gt; and a good &amp;lsquo;ol &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Solid-state_drive&#34;&gt;SSD&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:7&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; But moving them to Google was a mistake - they are the original surveillance capitlist! They are now housed on private file storage.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Hosting Events&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:8&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:8&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Email invitations, using my new people database! And maybe an online form for RSVPs&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Birthdays&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Added the most important ones to my calendar, yearly recurring&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/saved/&#34;&gt;Saved&lt;/a&gt; posts and links&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;I already tend to a vibrant lists ecosystem&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:9&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:9&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Groups&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Most of these are dead, some are stupid meme groups, and while others have no replacement, it&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I had a meaningful exchange there.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;My Dad&amp;rsquo;s Jeopardy Video&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t worry, I &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/5TP3-UT6eco&#34;&gt;posted it to Youtube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, I am finding so far that the sum of these parts is greater than Facebook&amp;rsquo;s whole, especially considering all of the contextual issues I discussed in the first part of this post. Once I had done all the prep, I also did &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/dyi&#34;&gt;one final download of all my information&lt;/a&gt;, just to be careful, and backed it up on my SSD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://natehn.com/fb5.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;A photo of me with two other people, with mountains visible in the distance. Faces have been obscured.&#34;/&gt; &lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;A photo of me with two other people, with mountains visible in the distance. Faces have been obscured.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For another guide on leaving and/or limiting social media, check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.humanetech.com/take-control&#34;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt; from the Center for Humane Technology.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:10&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:10&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;10&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; I think it is also worth it to think about securing your Internet use more broadly, not just in terms of social media use. I &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.fracturedatlas.org/security-privacy-tools-artistic-collaboration&#34;&gt;wrote about secure tools on Fractured Atlas&amp;rsquo;s blog&lt;/a&gt;, and I will be writing more about digital security here on this blog as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;whats-next&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently told a close friend of mine (via SMS) that I am in the process of leaving Facebook for good. Their response? &amp;ldquo;This is such a good step.&amp;rdquo; I also know, however, that this might seem like a &amp;ldquo;lone-wolf&amp;rdquo; escape from the social obligations of the modern public square. Do I have a responsibility to shout my opinions - which are completely correct of course (lol) - into the social media void? No. Taking into account the ways my mental and emotional health are affected and the deep damage these systems have done to our society,&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:11&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:11&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;11&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; I see no way that Facebook should continue to be part of my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://natehn.com/fb6.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;A photo of me sitting at a table with six other people. I am turning around to face the camera. Faces are obscured.&#34;/&gt; &lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;A photo of me sitting at a table with six other people. I am turning around to face the camera. Faces are obscured.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, I&amp;rsquo;m not interested in losing personal connections. In fact, thinking about this has highlighted their importance. I&amp;rsquo;ve never been more conscious of how valuable my real, direct relationships are - even those that have long been dormant. So my plan is to to reach out to each remaining Facebook friend one by one, via Messenger, and:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let them know I am leaving the platform&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explain why I am leaving (with a link to this post and &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thesocialdilemma.com/&#34;&gt;The Social Dilemma&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exchange non-social-media contact information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Share a link to my &lt;a href=&#34;https://buttondown.email/natehn&#34;&gt;quarterly newletter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(At some point I&amp;rsquo;ll set an official date for my Facebook shutdown, leaving plenty of time for folks to respond.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just because I am leaving a &amp;ldquo;social network&amp;rdquo; does not mean I am done with networks or socialization. And I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;em&gt;definitely&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://natehn.com/posts/this-website/&#34;&gt;not done with the Internet&lt;/a&gt;. One network that I will be joining to start is a cool index of arts and open-source focused personal blogs called a &lt;a href=&#34;https://webring.xxiivv.com/#random&#34;&gt;webring&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to learning about other options, too. See you there!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film is headlined by the creators of many of the tools we use every day, from Infinite Scroll to Google Drive to Facebook&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Like&amp;rdquo; Button. They articulate many of the ways that these platforms, due to their drive to monetize users and make a profit, cause enormous problems from the individual level all the way up to the global scale. Some of the little dramatizations are over-the-top&amp;hellip;you can skip them and still get a lot out of the film. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, this was only on mobile, since I already had &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jordwest/news-feed-eradicator&#34;&gt;News Feed Eradicator&lt;/a&gt; running on my desktop. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was eventually able to stop the latter behavior after switching the majority of my mobile browsing activity over to &lt;a href=&#34;https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/focus&#34;&gt;Firefox Focus&lt;/a&gt;, which does not keep me logged in. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favorite is &lt;a href=&#34;https://feedly.com/&#34;&gt;Feedly&lt;/a&gt; for iOS, but there are TONS of options. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Airtable provides a bunch of great features that Facebook does not, such as useful categorization and adding in people&amp;rsquo;s contact information. It is very flexible. I mixed the records I could &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/dyi&#34;&gt;download from Facebook&lt;/a&gt; with exports of my phone and email contacts. I merged them manually, which was the most time-intensive part of the process. I also categorized folks along the way by how I know them (WRFL, UK, NYC, KOG, Fishers, etc.). &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:6&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing to note is that downloading your data does not download other people&amp;rsquo;s photos that you are tagged in, and might not download photos that are in private events. Downloading public videos you are tagged in &lt;a href=&#34;https://fbdown.net/&#34;&gt;is easy&lt;/a&gt;, but private videos &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.techgyd.com/download-private-facebook-videos/40841/&#34;&gt;require a special technique&lt;/a&gt;. I went through and downloaded each one, one at a time! I&amp;rsquo;m a digital packrat, don&amp;rsquo;t @ me. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:7&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The big-tech program, &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatransferproject.dev/&#34;&gt;Data Transfer Project&lt;/a&gt; (which to some degree entrenches these companies, by the way), was very convenient. I was able to transfer photos directly from Facebook to Google. I am not sharing photos and tagging people on Facebook the way I used to, so Google Photos was sure to cover my needs. (I was not thinking, when I wrote this, about surveillance capitalism.) I keep them for myself, and back them up on the SSD, and I can share them with folks from my file storage if needed. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:8&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those of you who remember the old Housewarming parties, don&amp;rsquo;t worry, I screenshot all of those event pages for posterity. I also saved the full list of events that I attended or was &amp;ldquo;interested&amp;rdquo; in (yuck!) for my own records. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:8&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were quite a few old links and posts festering from years past. I went through them and saved anything I was still interested in. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:9&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:10&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have also made efforts to limit my use of other social media platforms including Instagram, Twitter, and Youtube, although my use of those platforms has always paled in comparison to my use of Facebook. Taking care of my Youtube use (mostly for video game videos and electronic music performances) is next on my list. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:10&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:11&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though it &lt;a href=&#34;https://stratechery.com/2020/anti-monopoly-vs-antitrust/&#34;&gt;may not be, technically, a monopoly&lt;/a&gt;, Facebook and other tech giants absolutely represent a &lt;a href=&#34;https://aeon.co/videos/a-handful-of-executives-control-the-attention-economy-time-for-attentive-resistance&#34;&gt;concentration of power&lt;/a&gt;. Facebook also engages in &lt;a href=&#34;https://themarkup.org/election-2020/2020/10/29/facebook-political-ad-targeting-algorithm-prices-trump-biden&#34;&gt;practices that are bad for democracy&lt;/a&gt;. Certainly, fake news is enabled by these technologies. There have been plenty of controversies around their censorship of things, lack of censorship of other things, and generally a great deal of concern about their content moderation &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theverge.com/2019/2/25/18229714/cognizant-facebook-content-moderator-interviews-trauma-working-conditions-arizona&#34;&gt;policies and practices&lt;/a&gt;. The list of societal issues is long, and I won&amp;rsquo;t go all the way into it here. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:11&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Memes</title>
      <link>https://natehn.com/posts/on-memes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://natehn.com/posts/on-memes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This meme repository is presented by&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/0xojO-4VFPw&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A meme is an idea. A trend. A &amp;ldquo;unit of cultural information.&amp;rdquo; Some of my favorite memes are tiny, but dense with content - a juxtaposition of surprising and hilarious images and sounds, crammed into just a short span of time and space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/CMNry4PE93Y&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some were never meant to be funny.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/rY8DSFZ08JQ&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;while others build upon found footage to take it to the next level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/E_dIo1sDA_Q&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of them ask questions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/G7RgN9ijwE4&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(more than once)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/dXidW7fEH8g&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Questions about reality:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/I0DDWJNHLLA&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;about time:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/1Zn958rN-H4&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;and about existence itself:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/fFtgc0CdvJA&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Memes ask &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Q67SozSkzuU&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although they may not have the answers, they still bring us joy, even in the small things:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/jeGTt08xdWA&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like dog ears:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/q8tZIN0GgoI&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Elephant shrews - singing:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Dc6pAuRiyVo&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hilarious pranks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/aMmAsqtGRmk&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And classics that make you crack up EVERY SINGLE TIME.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/EShUeudtaFg&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Thanks for coming to my TED Talk. For more meme content, check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://palmsandpowerlines.substack.com/p/all-star-by-smash-mouth-but-its-my&#34;&gt;my friend Cody&amp;rsquo;s compilation&lt;/a&gt;. You&amp;rsquo;ll never know if you don&amp;rsquo;t  go.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Land Acknowledgment</title>
      <link>https://natehn.com/posts/land-acknowledgment/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://natehn.com/posts/land-acknowledgment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-land&#34;&gt;The Land&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the things I have been thinking about over the last few years is the politics of the land. I have learned a lot about the way that my society - American society - came to be. I have also started to learn more deeply about the concept of justice. In the history of my people, there is much injustice - and we are the ones who perpetrate it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The land where I (and &lt;a href=&#34;https://natehn.com/posts/this-website/#the-physical-server&#34;&gt;these website files&lt;/a&gt;) reside suffers under the weight of countless injustices - layers and layers of harm done by me, my people, and our ancestors. Today, I am starting by acknowledging my relationship with the very first: the theft of this continent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The so-called &amp;ldquo;New World&amp;rdquo;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; was stolen over the course of the last 600 years. Descendants of this land&amp;rsquo;s original inhabitants live here still - they are my friends and colleagues. The very least we can do is examine the generations of unimaginable pain our own ancestors may have caused them, and look within ourselves to connect those histories with our present reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://natehn.com/north-america.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;A screenshot of North America from Native-Land.ca.&#34;/&gt; &lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;A screenshot of North America from Native-Land.ca.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the first steps to showing solidarity with Indigenous peoples as a settler is to explore the histories of the land that you inhabit. Many organizations also choose to acknowledge those histories before public events and performances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a way, these blog posts are my &amp;ldquo;performances.&amp;rdquo; The website, the venue. If the Internet is not some other world, but rather Real Life - if things that are said and done here have an effect on the physical world, and they do - then we need to take our online activity as seriously as we would our daily physical lives. Thus, I begin this acknowledgment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mannahatta&#34;&gt;Mannahatta&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The island on which I live, and where this website’s little server is found, is home to 1.6 million people. It is covered in massive buildings, crowded streets, and crisscrossed with thrumming subterranean transportation tunnels. In some ways, it is the most important city in the world. It is the seat of power for Western capitalism, and we call it Manhattan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://natehn.com/new-york.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;A screenshot of New York and the surrounding area from Native-Land.ca.&#34;/&gt; &lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;A screenshot of New York and the surrounding area from Native-Land.ca.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before a convergence of circumstances led to this city&amp;rsquo;s international wealth and fame, and before my people came to these lands, it was also well known, but not for its commercial prowess. Then called Mannahatta, or “land of many hills,&amp;quot;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; it was known for its natural beauty and was home to the Lenni Lenape people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When my people arrived, they displaced the Lenni Lenape - and all Native people - from these lands. The act itself, and all of the murder, deception, war, and genocide that took place throughout this campaign of &amp;ldquo;discovery&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;destiny,&amp;rdquo; are probably unforgivable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Manhattan, the story was one of deceit - fitting, for a city known for its shady real estate. According to Western histories, my people &amp;ldquo;paid&amp;rdquo; the Canarsie tribe $24 for the whole island.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Whether or not you can actually buy land from a people that do not believe in private land ownership was irrelevant. Manhattan&amp;rsquo;s origins lie in theft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-people&#34;&gt;My People&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For many White Americans, family history is mythical and vague. They are probably from Europe, but &lt;em&gt;when&lt;/em&gt; their ancestors arrived here and &lt;em&gt;where&lt;/em&gt;, specifically, they came from are lost to time. Not so for my family. My dad has taken the time to dig deep into our family history. Having done very little of the work, I benefit in knowing exactly where I come from. The first step of acknowledging my ancestors&amp;rsquo; mistakes - knowing them - is already most of the way complete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I lived in New York, I was in present-day Kentucky, Indiana, and Illinois. Those unceded lands were originally home to the Miami, Oceti Sakowin&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, Shawnee, Osage, and Cherokee. For several generations before, my people lived in Illinois, farming the original lands of the Peoria, Neshnabe, Meshkwahkihaki, and Sauk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://natehn.com/midwest.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;A screenshot of the American Midwest from Native-Land.ca.&#34;/&gt; &lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;A screenshot of the American Midwest from Native-Land.ca.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of my ancestors arrived to this continent as recently as 150 years ago, from Germany and Sweden. Other Western and Central European forebears came to these lands over the preceding centuries. The settling of my ancestors in lands formerly home to Native nations was part of a centuries long campaign to destroy Native communities that continues to this day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps most relevant among my ancestors was the Puritan missionary John Eliot, who sought to Westernize and “civilize” the Massachusett people, causing irreparable harm by forcing them to reject their culture and therefore their economy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Haudenosaunee writer wrote that missionaries “serve as lay ambassadors of their culture, splitting off individuals from families, families from villages, villages from nations, one by one.”&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:5&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; This was absolutely the case with the “Praying Indians” of Massachusetts. Eliot&amp;rsquo;s ideas, while less violent than the colonial norms of the time, prefigured the deeply harmful policies of Americanization that would arise 150 years later.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:6&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;NOTE:&lt;/em&gt; Although I happen to know some of the specifics of my ancestry, when I say &amp;ldquo;my people,&amp;rdquo; I mean White people. I benefit not only from the terrible actions of my direct ancestors, but from actions of White society as well. It is our arrival, our culture, our actions that have driven this world to the brink.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;black-lives&#34;&gt;Black Lives&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When my people arrived on this land, they brought others with them. They brought enslaved African people - ancestors of my friends and colleagues - to run their extractive capitalist enterprises. The crimes done by my people to Black people are too many to name, both during slavery and since.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:7&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; The enslavement - kidnapping - of Black people is yet another of the original sins of my people on these lands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://natehn.com/slave-ship.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;Slave ship diagram, first printed as a broadside in England in 1789.&#34;/&gt; &lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Slave ship diagram, first printed as a broadside in England in 1789.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of my ancestors lived in the American South back before the Civil War. Various branches of that family &amp;ldquo;owned&amp;rdquo; a few enslaved African people, over the course of generations. Since they were not major slaveholders, there are few records to be found. When they moved to southern Illinois, a free state, they likely sold them or gave them away.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:8&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:8&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has been 400 years since kidnapped Black people were first brought here. Modern slavery lives on in our prison systems, and systemic injustice is baked into every aspect of modern American life. Police brutality, the most public and violent way in which Black communities are torn apart, is only the tip of the iceberg.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To all of these injustices, I say this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our ancestors made many mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our people committed many crimes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is much work to be done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;history-is-alive&#34;&gt;History Is Alive&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(shifting from acknowledgment to discussion)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my favorite book series, &lt;em&gt;The Malazan Book of the Fallen&lt;/em&gt;, history is alive. It is personified by gods, ascendants, and other immortal beings, each with their own story. In some ways, they are more like impulses than characters - or ideas that just won&amp;rsquo;t die. They walk the earth, drifting from conflict to conflict, living myths long detached from the circumstances that forged them, seeking always an elusive sense of fulfillment that never comes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good lives on and adapts, but so too does evil. Like those ghoulish immortals of the Malazan world, some of our darkest ideas, as a species, never seem to go away. Supremacy. Scarcity. Materialism. Individualism. Some folks say that those who do not know the past are doomed to repeat it - and perhaps they are right. Today, however, it is as clear as ever that the past is not done with us, and knowing it is not enough. The evils of the past are not gone, and will not be going away anytime soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lie of my people - White Supremacy - lives on, adapting and thriving at every level of American society. The past, in our world, may not walk or talk as it does in the Malazan one, but that makes it all the more challenging to defeat. In those moments when we feel we may have finally vanquished it,&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:9&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:9&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; we are at our weakest. Sometimes the resurgence of our most evil ideas is so overwhelming, and so entrenched, that it confounds even our greatest thinkers. White Supremacy&amp;rsquo;s roots run deep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;actions&#34;&gt;Actions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A member of the Haudenosaunee, known by my people as the Six Nations Iroquois, wrote a few decades ago that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For over 300 years, our people have been under a virtual state of siege. During this entire time we have never once given up our struggle. Our strategies have, of necessity, changed. But the will and determination to continue on remains the same.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:10&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:10&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;10&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My ancestors were actively involved in this siege. Even as I seek justice in my work, and seek to support Native futures, I acknowledge that by remaining on this land I remain complicit in a crime that can never be undone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actions speak louder than words. I am on this journey, and would love for you to join me. I recommend that you start by reading &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://nativevoicesbooks.com/content/basic-call-consciousness&#34;&gt;Basic Call to Consciousness&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, the Haudenosaunee book from which I pulled the above quotations. If you want to explore the process of land acknowledgment, I recommend these resources:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://landacknowledgements.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/Acknowledgement-Guide-finalfinal.pdf&#34;&gt;Guide to Indigenous Land and Territorial Acknowledgements for Cultural Institutions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://native-land.ca/territory-acknowledgement/&#34;&gt;Territory Acknowledgement&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://usdac.us/nativeland&#34;&gt;Honor Native Land: A Guide and Call to Acknowledgment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://native-land.ca/&#34;&gt;Native-Land&lt;/a&gt; website is also a great place to start when researching the original inhabitants of the land under your feet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Change begins with acknowledgment, but it does not stop there. We must stand alongside Native and Black activists and support their movements. We must offer our time, skills, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://mannahattafund.org/&#34;&gt;resources&lt;/a&gt; to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://aich.org/&#34;&gt;Native&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://actionnetwork.org/fundraising/louisville-community-bail-fund/&#34;&gt;Black&lt;/a&gt; organizations in our communities. And we must always continue to learn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you aren&amp;rsquo;t sure where to start, start with money. Pay a &lt;a href=&#34;https://resourcegeneration.org/indigenous-land-tax-one-way-that-rg-strives-to-create-policies-that-reflect-our-values/&#34;&gt;land tax&lt;/a&gt;! Support &lt;a href=&#34;https://decolonialatlas.wordpress.com/2020/09/19/indigenous-eateries/&#34;&gt;Native&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eatokra.com/&#34;&gt;Black&lt;/a&gt;-&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.afrovegansociety.org/vegan-restaurants&#34;&gt;owned&lt;/a&gt; businesses! Reparations are not the only answer, but they are a fine place to begin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;~&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would be happy to talk with you about the above acknowledgment and discussion - especially you, my fellow White people. We have a lot to learn. Feel free to &lt;a href=&#34;https://natehn.com&#34;&gt;reach out&lt;/a&gt; if you want to chat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These lands are known to some Northeastern Native peoples as Turtle Island. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To this day, the city sits high upon its magical hills. In Central Park you can see its beautiful schist dipping to the south, marking the passage of glaciers from thousands of years ago. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thirteen.org/dutchny/interactives/manhattan-island/&#34;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pronounced Och-et-eeshak-oh-win. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://nativevoicesbooks.com/content/basic-call-consciousness&#34;&gt;Basic Call to Consciousness&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:6&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John Eliot is still a celebrated ancestor among many members of my family, both as an missionary and as a linguist. I once shared my direct descendance from him as a &amp;ldquo;fun fact.&amp;rdquo; I now look back at his actions with shame. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:7&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be clear, I believe in the possibility of a world without prisons, jails, and police. I believe we must invest in over-policed communities. Black lives matter, full-stop. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:8&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course I would like to think that they freed them, but there is no reason to think so. Some of their cousins continued to own slaves back in Virginia. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:8&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;E.g., the 2008 election. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:9&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:10&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://nativevoicesbooks.com/content/basic-call-consciousness&#34;&gt;Basic Call to Consciousness&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:10&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This Website, and How To Build Your Own</title>
      <link>https://natehn.com/posts/this-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://natehn.com/posts/this-website/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;origins&#34;&gt;Origins&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This website is just a bunch of little files living on a tiny computer that sits on my living room bookcase. It plugs into the wall and my router, and all it does all day is serve up these website files to whoever requests them. For most servers out there (shared hosting, virtual private servers, and the like), it is a thankless job. But I try to give my little Lime2 single-board computer some attention every so often. A little bit of gratitude can go a long way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the years, I&amp;rsquo;ve built a few different personal websites. First, there was the college résumé site, &lt;a href=&#34;https://natehn.com/posts/this-website/#origins&#34;&gt;nathanhewitt.net&lt;/a&gt;. Then there were other short-lived iterations: the music-focused &lt;a href=&#34;https://natehn.com/posts/this-website/#origins&#34;&gt;auohm.us&lt;/a&gt; (before I stopped using the moniker AUOHM), the simplistic &lt;a href=&#34;https://natehn.com/posts/this-website/#origins&#34;&gt;nthnh.co&lt;/a&gt;, and the Web 1.0 &lt;a href=&#34;https://natehn.com/posts/this-website/#origins&#34;&gt;omg.lol/nathan&lt;/a&gt;. On the backend, I tried Wordpress, Squarespace, Wix, and others. I also put together plenty of simple, WYSIWYG websites when I was doing freelance graphic design in college.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this website, I originally wanted to self-host in order to learn &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt;. As I built the site, however, I started to come up with other reasons. Over time, a constellation of motivations started to form:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My desire to learn basic Linux programming (&lt;code&gt;bash&lt;/code&gt;) and related technology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trying to get away from corporate-owned social media platforms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finding my written voice again&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experimenting with solar power&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sharing what I have learned; sharing what I am learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Having a home on the web&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Natehn&amp;rdquo; is a new online moniker that mixes three letters of my first and last names. I feel that, as my public engagement with the Internet begins to change, a new name will help to separate the new from the old. (The similarity to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tehn&#34;&gt;Brian Crabtree&amp;rsquo;s moniker&lt;/a&gt; is purely coincidental.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;building-your-own&#34;&gt;Building Your Own&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in building and hosting your own website the way I did, I would be &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:nthnhwtt@gmail.com&#34;&gt;happy to help&lt;/a&gt;. Some basic directions are below. As you go, be sure to also check in on the core documentation for &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.armbian.com/&#34;&gt;Armbian&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/getting-started/quick-start/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;. You may also want to learn the basics of &lt;a href=&#34;https://techlearningcollective.com/foundations/&#34;&gt;the command line&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4d77bxpgB5c&#34;&gt;bash&lt;/a&gt;. Finally, I recommend checking out the guides at &lt;a href=&#34;https://homebrewserver.club/&#34;&gt;the homebrewserver.club&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I made a lot of mistakes along the way - mistakes that hopefully you can avoid. Because of various unforced errors, I ended up trying out three different web server programs (Nginx and Apache, before settling on Caddy) and three different static website builders (Pelican and Jekyll, settling on Hugo). When I was at my wit&amp;rsquo;s end, all I had to do was &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/63351978/css-not-loading-for-self-hosted-nginx-with-jekyll-hugo-site/63359674&#34;&gt;ask for help&lt;/a&gt;. (Thank you @randomsock!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-physical-server&#34;&gt;The Physical Server&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember: there&amp;rsquo;s no such thing as &amp;ldquo;the cloud.&amp;rdquo; There are just a bunch of computers that someone else owns. This one, however, is owned by me. Following the lead of Low←Tech Magazine, I used an &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.olimex.com/wiki/A20-OLinuXino-LIME2&#34;&gt;Olimex Lime2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; running on a variant of Debian (itself a distribution of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linux_distribution&#34;&gt;Linux&lt;/a&gt;) called Armbian. Following Armbian&amp;rsquo;s instructions, I used Balena Etcher to &amp;ldquo;flash&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.armbian.com/olimex-lime-2/&#34;&gt;the image&lt;/a&gt; onto a MicroSD card.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://natehn.com/server.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;My small Olimex server sits amidst my partner&amp;amp;rsquo;s Buddha collection on a bookcase with a LiPo battery zip-tied to the top.&#34;/&gt; &lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;My small Olimex server sits amidst my partner&amp;rsquo;s Buddha collection on a bookcase with a LiPo battery zip-tied to the top.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Insert the MicroSD card, plug in your power adapter, connect it your router with an ethernet cable, connect mouse, keyboard, and HDMI, and you&amp;rsquo;re up and running! After my initial configuration (see below) I always connected to the server via SSH, so there was no need to keep it connected to mouse, keyboard, or monitor.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My basic configuration of the server included logging in as root (pw: 1234) and updating its password, creating a username and password for myself with &lt;code&gt;sudo&lt;/code&gt; admin permissions, logging in, and then making sure everything was up to date via &lt;code&gt;sudo apt-get update &amp;amp;&amp;amp; sudo apt-get upgrade&lt;/code&gt;. I then went ahead and &lt;a href=&#34;https://linuxconfig.org/how-to-setup-a-static-ip-address-on-debian-linux&#34;&gt;set a Static IP (LAN) address&lt;/a&gt; for the Lime2&amp;rsquo;s ethernet port so that it would always be accessible at the same address. I also installed a firewall called UFW and configured it to allow SSH, HTTP, and HTTPS through (&lt;code&gt;sudo ufw allow 22 80 443&lt;/code&gt;). We&amp;rsquo;ll get into more of the networking stuff a little bit later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-static-website&#34;&gt;The Static Website&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Setting up Hugo was simple as could be. I followed &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/getting-started/installing#debian-and-ubuntu&#34;&gt;their directions&lt;/a&gt; to install (&lt;code&gt;sudo apt-get install hugo&lt;/code&gt;). Then I used the Quick Start documentation, creating a directory for my site (&lt;code&gt;mkdir&lt;/code&gt;), &lt;code&gt;cd&lt;/code&gt;-ed into that directory, and created the site using &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/getting-started/quick-start/#step-2-create-a-new-site&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;hugo new site quickstart&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a theme, I am using a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/natehn/blog-theme&#34;&gt;lightly-modified&lt;/a&gt; version of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/monkeyWzr/hugo-theme-cactus&#34;&gt;Cactus&lt;/a&gt;. Hugo has &lt;a href=&#34;https://themes.gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;plenty of themes available&lt;/a&gt;, as well as information on &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/getting-started/quick-start/#step-3-add-a-theme&#34;&gt;how to install them&lt;/a&gt;. All my modifications were done in true amateur fashion - trial and error.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hugo has plenty more information in their Quick Start guide. Once the site was ready, I ran &lt;code&gt;hugo&lt;/code&gt; in the main directory to build the site in a directory called &lt;code&gt;public&lt;/code&gt;. If you&amp;rsquo;ve been following along, your root directory will probably something like &lt;code&gt;home/user/blogfolder/public&lt;/code&gt;. You&amp;rsquo;ll need that info when you set up your webserver.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;networking&#34;&gt;Networking&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make sure that you are ready to receive external traffic, you will need to set up a DCHP reservation and port forwarding (ports 80 and 443) in your router. This basically ensures that folks who connect to your router for the purpose of getting to your website will be directed by the router to your server. The specific process for this will depend on your router and Internet Service Provider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While doing this, go ahead and make a note of the WAN IP Address for your router. You will need this when pointing your domain name at your server. Be aware, unless you set a Static WAN IP address through your Internet Service Provider, it is possible for your WAN address to change. If your website goes down, that could be one of the first things to check.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;your-domain-name&#34;&gt;Your Domain Name&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, of course, you should buy a domain name. Then with your domain name registrar, or wherever you manage the DNS records for your domain, make an A record (a.k.a. &amp;ldquo;address&amp;rdquo; record) pointing to the WAN IP address of your router. The process for doing this depends on your provider. If you are using the same configuration as me, you should also create a URL Redirect record with the hostname &amp;ldquo;www&amp;rdquo; redirecting to the non-www URL of your website (e.g., &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com&#34;&gt;https://example.com&lt;/a&gt;). It can then take 24-48 hours for your new DNS settings to &amp;ldquo;propogate&amp;rdquo; and go into effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-webserver&#34;&gt;The Webserver&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Caddy will be our webserver. To set up Caddy, we will follow the installation directions for Debian put together by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tecmint.com/install-caddy-web-server-in-centos-ubuntu/&#34;&gt;TecMint&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Install Caddy:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;echo &amp;quot;deb [trusted=yes] https://apt.fury.io/caddy/ /&amp;quot; \
    | sudo tee -a /etc/apt/sources.list.d/caddy-fury.list
sudo apt update
sudo apt install caddy
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Start Caddy:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;systemctl start caddy
systemctl enable caddy
systemctl status caddy
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Configure Caddy:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open up the configuration file at &lt;code&gt;/etc/caddy/Caddyfile&lt;/code&gt; with your favorite text editor (e.g., vim, nano). Change &lt;code&gt;:80&lt;/code&gt; to your domain (&lt;code&gt;natehn.com&lt;/code&gt; for example) and the root to the root of your public site, such as &lt;code&gt;home/user/blogfolder/public&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Restart Caddy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Restart Caddy with this new configuration via &lt;code&gt;systemctl reload caddy&lt;/code&gt;. Your website should be up and running!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note Regarding SSL Certificates&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Caddy should take care of your SSL certificate, which is used for HTTPS, automatically on your behalf. If you have trouble with it, check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://certbot.eff.org/lets-encrypt/debianbuster-other&#34;&gt;these instructions from Certbot&lt;/a&gt;. (I did this out of order and got a certificate back when I was using Nginx as my webserver.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;writing&#34;&gt;Writing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For putting posts together, I recommend learning a simple plaintext syntax called Markdown. Hugo uses Markdown to turn plaintext into html.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; It makes writing up an article so much easier. Posts composed using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.markdownguide.org/basic-syntax/&#34;&gt;Markdown&amp;rsquo;s easy syntax&lt;/a&gt; and dropped into blog&amp;rsquo;s directory will become low-weight html pages on your static website. Hugo also has a handy &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/content-management/shortcodes/&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;figure&lt;/code&gt; shortcode&lt;/a&gt; to help you insert images.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://natehn.com/tasman.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;A beautiful sunrise at a campground near Abel Tasman National Park.&#34;/&gt; &lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;A beautiful sunrise at a campground near Abel Tasman National Park.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For focused writing, I use a lightweight plaintext editor called &lt;a href=&#34;https://hundredrabbits.itch.io/left&#34;&gt;Left&lt;/a&gt;, by the awesome sailboatin&amp;rsquo; folks at HundredRabbits. I also use &lt;a href=&#34;https://gottcode.org/focuswriter/&#34;&gt;FocusWriter&lt;/a&gt; on occasion. But any plaintext editor will do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you have a website up and running, you&amp;rsquo;re at the last step: content. In our modern capitalist internet, the content mills never stop running. Blog posts of a certain length, with certain keywords (and questionable value), are used to optimize companies&amp;rsquo; search engine position (the proverbial neverending scramble for &amp;ldquo;SEO&amp;rdquo;). And in this side-hustle culture, it sometimes feels like you have to compete to survive. (I&amp;rsquo;ve certainly felt the pressure before!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to be like this. This site is a start. It is a forum: not content, but discussion - even if it is one-way. A place that is open and honest, especially about imperfections and mistakes. Let&amp;rsquo;s see where it leads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I chose this board based on the recommendation of Low←Tech Magazine and, as they mention, because of all the advantages related to how it is powered. It can provide additional information and can connect directly to a LiPo battery. Along with the board itself, I purchased the case they make for the board and the correct power supply. Separately, I also purchased a 3.7V 6600mAh Lithium Ion battery pack with a JST 2-pin cable attached. Although they say it is a genuine JST connector, I still have trouble disconnecting it sometimes. Not a big deal - I  don&amp;rsquo;t plan to disconnect it often. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On my Windows machine, I use Putty and WinSCP to connect to the Lime2 wirelessly from my computer. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is just simple stuff like changing the copyright line to allow for a Creative Commons license and changing the favicon and logo. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.markdownguide.org/tools/hugo/&#34;&gt;Hugo Markdown Support&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
