<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>natehn~</title>
    <link>https://natehn.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on natehn~</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>nathan hewitt Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International (CC BY-NC-SA 4.0)</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://natehn.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Connect</title>
      <link>https://natehn.com/connect/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://natehn.com/connect/</guid>
      <description>Open Invitation Cold email me! I&amp;rsquo;d love to hear what you have to say. Here are some reasons to reach out to me:
 To introduce yourself To share something I might be interested in To talk nonprofits, activism, art, music, technology, politics, etc. You loved/hated something I wrote I&amp;rsquo;m wrong, and you&amp;rsquo;re willing to tell me how To notify me of an error You&amp;rsquo;d like to hang if/when I go traveling  Or maybe it is none of these.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Studio (Nov. 2020)</title>
      <link>https://natehn.com/posts/music-studio-nov-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://natehn.com/posts/music-studio-nov-2020/</guid>
      <description>My music studio (i.e., a little corner of our little office) is ever-changing. Instruments and gear come and go. Workflows ebb and&amp;hellip;flow. This is the first post in a &amp;ldquo;music studio&amp;rdquo; series where we check in on what tools I&amp;rsquo;m currently using for my audio work.1
Gear Because of the limited space in my NYC apartment, my music studio is relatively small, occupying just 1/3 of the space in the &amp;ldquo;office&amp;rdquo; of our 2BR living space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leaving Facebook</title>
      <link>https://natehn.com/posts/leaving-facebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://natehn.com/posts/leaving-facebook/</guid>
      <description>A photo of me at a bowling alley.
  Why Although there have been plenty of fun moments on the platform, and meaningful, valuable interactions, the truth is that I&amp;rsquo;ve spent most of my time scrolling, searching, looking for something that was never there. When I look back, my memory of Facebook is primarily connected with a deep social anxiety. The attention-grabbing notifications. The rollercoaster of self-worth. Every minute without a &amp;ldquo;like&amp;rdquo; was a failure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Memes</title>
      <link>https://natehn.com/posts/on-memes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://natehn.com/posts/on-memes/</guid>
      <description>This meme repository is presented by&amp;hellip;
  A meme is an idea. A trend. A &amp;ldquo;unit of cultural information.&amp;rdquo; Some of my favorite memes are tiny, but dense with content - a juxtaposition of surprising and hilarious images and sounds, crammed into just a short span of time and space.
  Some were never meant to be funny.
  &amp;hellip;while others build upon found footage to take it to the next level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feed</title>
      <link>https://natehn.com/feed/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://natehn.com/feed/</guid>
      <description>RSS The quickest way to get an update when I post new writings is to follow the RSS feed.1
I recommend receiving RSS alerts by email, through a tool like Blogtrottr.2 Or you can add it to an RSS Reader3 of your choice!
Website Monitoring An option - other than checking manually - that does not involve RSS is using a web monitoring app to check this website peiodically to see if updates have been made.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Land Acknowledgment</title>
      <link>https://natehn.com/posts/land-acknowledgment/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://natehn.com/posts/land-acknowledgment/</guid>
      <description>The Land One of the things I have been thinking about over the last few years is the politics of the land. I have learned a lot about the way that my society - American society - came to be. I have also started to learn more deeply about the concept of justice. In the history of my people, there is much injustice - and we are the ones who perpetrate it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This Website, and How To Build Your Own</title>
      <link>https://natehn.com/posts/this-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://natehn.com/posts/this-website/</guid>
      <description>Origins This website is just a bunch of little files living on a tiny computer that sits on my living room bookcase. It plugs into the wall and my router, and all it does all day is serve up these website files to whoever requests them. For most servers out there (shared hosting, virtual private servers, and the like), it is a thankless job. But I try to give my little Lime2 single-board computer some attention every so often.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://natehn.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://natehn.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello!   A photo of me.
  I am an ambient/improvising musician, erstwhile radio deejay, nonprofit worker, occasional activist, habitual researcher, amateur technologist, wannabe photographer, dormant designer, and born-&amp;lsquo;n-raised midwesterner
I also watch sports, play video games, and hang out with friends - and I regularly frequent the local grocery store. I use he/him pronouns.
Now (updated 2020-01-15) I&amp;rsquo;m in the midst of year three in NYC. Of course, being the city has been quite different under lockdown - it barely feels like I&amp;rsquo;m in New York!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>