<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>nathan&#39;s latest</title>
    <link>https://natehn.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on nathan&#39;s latest</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>nathan hewitt Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International (CC BY-NC-SA 4.0)</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://natehn.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Land Acknowledgment</title>
      <link>https://natehn.com/posts/land-acknowledgment/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://natehn.com/posts/land-acknowledgment/</guid>
      <description>The Land One of the things I have been thinking about over the last few years is the politics of the land. I have learned a lot about the way that my society - American society - came to be. I have also started to learn more deeply about the concept of justice. In the history of my people, there is much injustice - and we are the ones who perpetrate it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This Website, and How To Build Your Own</title>
      <link>https://natehn.com/posts/this-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://natehn.com/posts/this-website/</guid>
      <description>Origins This website is just a bunch of little files living on a tiny computer that sits on my living room bookcase. It plugs into the wall and my router, and all it does all day is serve up these website files to whoever requests them. For most servers out there (shared hosting, virtual private servers, and the like), it is a thankless job. But I try to give my little Lime2 single-board computer some attention every so often.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Follow the Blog</title>
      <link>https://natehn.com/follow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://natehn.com/follow/</guid>
      <description>How will you follow my work if I&amp;rsquo;m not posting it on Facebook (etc)? I&amp;rsquo;ve got three options for you.
Option 1: Sign Up for the Newsletter Click here to sign up for my equinoctial/solstitial (i.e., quarterly) newsletter.1
  A screenshot of the newsletter sign-up page superimposed over an image of a person covered in mail.
  Option 2: Follow Using RSS2 The quickest way to get an update when I post new writings is to follow its RSS feed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://natehn.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://natehn.com/about/</guid>
      <description>I am:
 ambient musician erstwhile radio deejay nonprofit worker occasional activist habitual researcher amateur technologist athletics aficionado native midwesterner  Feel free to reach out through the channels listed on the Home page. I&amp;rsquo;m also happy to communicate using PGP &amp;lt;3
~
This website is self-hosted on a tiny Linux computer using Hugo and Caddy. I recently experimented with solar powering it but right now it is plugged into the wall.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>