<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>the Internet on natehn~</title>
    <link>https://natehn.com/tags/the-internet/</link>
    <description>Recent content in the Internet on natehn~</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>nathan hewitt Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International (CC BY-NC-SA 4.0)</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://natehn.com/tags/the-internet/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Leaving Facebook</title>
      <link>https://natehn.com/posts/leaving-facebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://natehn.com/posts/leaving-facebook/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://natehn.com/fb1.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;A photo of me at a bowling alley.&#34;/&gt; &lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;A photo of me at a bowling alley.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why&#34;&gt;Why&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although there have been plenty of fun moments on the platform, and meaningful, valuable interactions, the truth is that I&amp;rsquo;ve spent most of my time scrolling, searching, looking for something that was never there. When I look back, my memory of Facebook is primarily connected with a deep social anxiety. The attention-grabbing notifications. The rollercoaster of self-worth. Every minute without a &amp;ldquo;like&amp;rdquo; was a failure. Every comment was a triumph. And even as I matured, those core feelings have never really left me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like many people, it took me a while to realize that the News Feed was not really a &amp;ldquo;public square.&amp;rdquo; My engagement with friends on the platform was governed by the whims of an algorithm that cared little for my health or the health of my relationships. Notifications did not signal authentic interactions, but rather served to keep me on the website. Every day, without my knowing it, the technology took advantage of my underlying psychology, using sophisticated, calculated tricks to hold my attention and show me more ads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://natehn.com/fb2.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;A photo of someone throwing water at me with a bucket.&#34;/&gt; &lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;A photo of someone throwing water at me with a bucket.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of you will be familiar with the saying that &amp;ldquo;If you aren&amp;rsquo;t paying for the product, you &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; the product.&amp;rdquo; In &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thesocialdilemma.com/&#34;&gt;The Social Dilemma&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; a documentary film about social media, Jaron Lanier puts a finer point on it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s the gradual, slight, imperceptible change in your own behavior and perception that is the product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who would I be if I had never joined Facebook? Would I be different? Definitely! But I don&amp;rsquo;t really know how, or in what way. So many of my deepest relationships have lived, at least in part, on a website whose goal is not to enrich my life, but rather to enrich itself. Every interaction I have had with friends and family on that platform is tainted by the fact that our connection was facilitated for the purpose of selling changes in our behavior to the highest bidder. For over a decade, almost all of my interpersonal communication was enabled and financed by persuasive technology and growth hacking. (This is surveillance capitalism, and it sucks.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://natehn.com/fb3.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;A group photo of me with five other people. Faces have been obscured.&#34;/&gt; &lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;A group photo of me with five other people. Faces have been obscured.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, leaving isn&amp;rsquo;t easy. Even though my use of Facebook has waned in various ways over the years, it still functions as a sort of rolodex, and as an archive of good times. When I first started thinking about leaving, a few thoughts kept pulling me back:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What if I want to talk to [person I haven&amp;rsquo;t spoken to in 10 years]?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How will I share about my life?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How will I look back at all those good memories and photos that are only on Facebook?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;basically: &amp;ldquo;What if I need it later?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook is a pathway to my past, with an (honestly) pretty good user interface, and it is hard to give up on that. This isn&amp;rsquo;t my first time trying to leave. But &lt;a href=&#34;https://psyche.co/guides/how-to-make-new-friends-when-youre-busy-with-adulthood&#34;&gt;making friends as an adult&lt;/a&gt; is hard enough as it is. I don&amp;rsquo;t need these companies to get involved in my social life by modifying my behavior - even modifying it by 0.01%. I&amp;rsquo;ll pass on leaving my self-esteem to the whims of their moneymaking algorithms. From here on, where I can, I want to engage as authentically as possible. I&amp;rsquo;m going to set my own boundaries. In so many ways, and for so many reasons, Facebook just isn&amp;rsquo;t cutting it. That&amp;rsquo;s it - I&amp;rsquo;m out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how&#34;&gt;How&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Facebook is so ingrained in my life, even after months of declining use, extricating it has been no easy task. I could quit the platform with no notice or preparation - cold turkey, like a couple of my closest friends - but I still feared losing touch with people who I only am connected with on Facebook, or losing track of the photos and memories that made me love it so much in the first place. As such, my goal is to replace all of the tools Facebook provides with my own, piece by piece.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://natehn.com/fb4.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;A photo of me with three other people. Inexplicably, I chose to face my chest away from the camera. Faces have been obscured.&#34;/&gt; &lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;A photo of me with three other people. Inexplicably, I chose to face my chest away from the camera. Faces have been obscured.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initially, when I was first thinking about the ways I engage with the platform, I ran into a post by my acquaintance (and Facebook friend) Sahar Massachi called &lt;a href=&#34;https://sahar.io/how-i-use-facebook/&#34;&gt;How I use Facebook&lt;/a&gt;. Since Sahar used to be an engineer on Facebook&amp;rsquo;s Civic team, I was intrigued and I followed a few of his suggestions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I told Facebook that I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to see ads anymore, over and over again, until I didn&amp;rsquo;t see as many ads&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I unliked all of my liked pages and only followed a few of them that were especially important to me&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I left most of my groups&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These changes were okay, but they didn&amp;rsquo;t release me from my core hang-ups with the platform. After another hour-long doom scroll on my phone, I deleted the mobile app. I had done this numerous times before, but it never stuck. I would be going to an event, or want to post a photo while out and about, and end up re-installing the app. Or I would just start opening up the mobile site in a browser.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the days of the pandemic, however, that was not a problem, and this time it worked. I&amp;rsquo;ve made it longer than ever before without using the mobile app, and I haven&amp;rsquo;t actually found that I need the platform at all. Now is my best chance to head off on my own - out into the unknown, a Facebook-less social world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;heres-how-ive-replaced-facebook&#34;&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s how I&amp;rsquo;ve replaced Facebook:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Facebook Feature&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;My Replacement&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Profile page&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://natehn.com/&#34;&gt;This website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Sharing updates and opinions&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Sending out a &lt;a href=&#34;https://buttondown.email/natehn&#34;&gt;quarterly newletter&lt;/a&gt; and posting on &lt;a href=&#34;https://natehn.com/posts/&#34;&gt;this blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Sharing memes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://natehn.com/posts/on-memes/&#34;&gt;Check it out&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Keeping up with the news&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Using an RSS reader&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; - just news, no comments section&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Database of people&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Making my own database on &lt;a href=&#34;https://airtable.com/&#34;&gt;Airtable&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:5&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Sharing artistic photos, sometimes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://vsco.co/natehnnn/gallery&#34;&gt;VSCO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;My personal photos&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:6&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; with friends and family&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://photos.google.com/&#34;&gt;Google Photos&lt;/a&gt; and a good &amp;lsquo;ol &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Solid-state_drive&#34;&gt;SSD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:7&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Hosting Events&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:8&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:8&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Email invitations, using my new people database! And maybe an online form for RSVPs&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Birthdays&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Added the most important ones to my calendar, yearly recurring&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/saved/&#34;&gt;Saved&lt;/a&gt; posts and links&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;I already tend to a vibrant lists ecosystem&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:9&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:9&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Groups&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Most of these are dead, some are stupid meme groups, and while others have no replacement, it&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I had a meaningful exchange there.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;My Dad&amp;rsquo;s Jeopardy Video&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t worry, I &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/5TP3-UT6eco&#34;&gt;posted it to Youtube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, I am finding so far that the sum of these parts is greater than Facebook&amp;rsquo;s whole, especially considering all of the contextual issues I discussed in the first part of this post. Once I had done all the prep, I also did &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/dyi&#34;&gt;one final download of all my information&lt;/a&gt;, just to be careful, and backed it up on my SSD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://natehn.com/fb5.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;A photo of me with two other people, with mountains visible in the distance. Faces have been obscured.&#34;/&gt; &lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;A photo of me with two other people, with mountains visible in the distance. Faces have been obscured.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For another guide on leaving and/or limiting social media, check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.humanetech.com/take-control&#34;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt; from the Center for Humane Technology.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:10&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:10&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;10&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; I think it is also worth it to think about securing your Internet use more broadly, not just in terms of social media use. I &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.fracturedatlas.org/security-privacy-tools-artistic-collaboration&#34;&gt;wrote about secure tools on Fractured Atlas&amp;rsquo;s blog&lt;/a&gt;, and I will be writing more about digital security here on this blog as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;whats-next&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently told a close friend of mine (via SMS) that I am in the process of leaving Facebook for good. Their response? &amp;ldquo;This is such a good step.&amp;rdquo; I also know, however, that this might seem like a &amp;ldquo;lone-wolf&amp;rdquo; escape from the social obligations of the modern public square. Do I have a responsibility to shout my opinions - which are completely correct of course (lol) - into the social media void? No. Taking into account the ways my mental and emotional health are affected and the deep damage these systems have done to our society,&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:11&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:11&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;11&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; I see no way that Facebook should continue to be part of my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://natehn.com/fb6.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;A photo of me sitting at a table with six other people. I am turning around to face the camera. Faces are obscured.&#34;/&gt; &lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;A photo of me sitting at a table with six other people. I am turning around to face the camera. Faces are obscured.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, I&amp;rsquo;m not interested in losing personal connections. In fact, thinking about this has highlighted their importance. I&amp;rsquo;ve never been more conscious of how valuable my real, direct relationships are - even those that have long been dormant. So my plan is to to reach out to each remaining Facebook friend one by one, via Messenger, and:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let them know I am leaving the platform&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explain why I am leaving (with a link to this post and &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thesocialdilemma.com/&#34;&gt;The Social Dilemma&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exchange non-social-media contact information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Share a link to my &lt;a href=&#34;https://buttondown.email/natehn&#34;&gt;quarterly newletter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(At some point I&amp;rsquo;ll set an official date for my Facebook shutdown, leaving plenty of time for folks to respond.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just because I am leaving a &amp;ldquo;social network&amp;rdquo; does not mean I am done with networks or socialization. And I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;em&gt;definitely&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://natehn.com/posts/this-website/&#34;&gt;not done with the Internet&lt;/a&gt;. One network that I will be joining to start is a cool index of arts and open-source focused personal blogs called a &lt;a href=&#34;https://webring.xxiivv.com/#random&#34;&gt;webring&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to learning about other options, too. See you there!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film is headlined by the creators of many of the tools we use every day, from Infinite Scroll to Google Drive to Facebook&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Like&amp;rdquo; Button. They articulate many of the ways that these platforms, due to their drive to monetize users and make a profit, cause enormous problems from the individual level all the way up to the global scale. Some of the little dramatizations are over-the-top&amp;hellip;you can skip them and still get a lot out of the film. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, this was only on mobile, since I already had &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jordwest/news-feed-eradicator&#34;&gt;News Feed Eradicator&lt;/a&gt; running on my desktop. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was eventually able to stop the latter behavior after switching the majority of my mobile browsing activity over to &lt;a href=&#34;https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/focus&#34;&gt;Firefox Focus&lt;/a&gt;, which does not keep me logged in. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favorite is &lt;a href=&#34;https://feedly.com/&#34;&gt;Feedly&lt;/a&gt; for iOS, but there are TONS of options. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Airtable provides a bunch of great features that Facebook does not, such as useful categorization and adding in people&amp;rsquo;s contact information. It is very flexible. I mixed the records I could &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/dyi&#34;&gt;download from Facebook&lt;/a&gt; with exports of my phone and email contacts. I merged them manually, which was the most time-intensive part of the process. I also categorized folks along the way by how I know them (WRFL, UK, NYC, KOG, Fishers, etc.). &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:6&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing to note is that downloading your data does not download other people&amp;rsquo;s photos that you are tagged in, and might not download photos that are in private events. Downloading public videos you are tagged in &lt;a href=&#34;https://fbdown.net/&#34;&gt;is easy&lt;/a&gt;, but private videos &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.techgyd.com/download-private-facebook-videos/40841/&#34;&gt;require a special technique&lt;/a&gt;. I went through and downloaded each one, one at a time! I&amp;rsquo;m a digital packrat, don&amp;rsquo;t @ me. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:7&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The big-tech program, &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatransferproject.dev/&#34;&gt;Data Transfer Project&lt;/a&gt; (which to some degree entrenches these companies, by the way), was very convenient. I was able to transfer photos directly from Facebook to Google. I am not sharing photos and tagging people on Facebook the way I used to, so Google Photos covers my needs. I keep them for myself, and back them up on the SSD, and Google Photos lets me share the photos with folks if needed. I know Google has plenty of issues as well&amp;hellip;but I&amp;rsquo;m taking all this one step at a time. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:8&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those of you who remember the old Housewarming parties, don&amp;rsquo;t worry, I screenshot all of those event pages for posterity. I also saved the full list of events that I attended or was &amp;ldquo;interested&amp;rdquo; in (yuck!) for my own records. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:8&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were quite a few old links and posts festering from years past. I went through them and saved anything I was still interested in. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:9&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:10&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have also made efforts to limit my use of other social media platforms including Instagram, Twitter, and Youtube, although my use of those platforms has always paled in comparison to my use of Facebook. Taking care of my Youtube use (mostly for video game videos and electronic music performances) is next on my list. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:10&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:11&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though it &lt;a href=&#34;https://stratechery.com/2020/anti-monopoly-vs-antitrust/&#34;&gt;may not be, technically, a monopoly&lt;/a&gt;, Facebook and other tech giants absolutely represent a &lt;a href=&#34;https://aeon.co/videos/a-handful-of-executives-control-the-attention-economy-time-for-attentive-resistance&#34;&gt;concentration of power&lt;/a&gt;. Facebook also engages in &lt;a href=&#34;https://themarkup.org/election-2020/2020/10/29/facebook-political-ad-targeting-algorithm-prices-trump-biden&#34;&gt;practices that are bad for democracy&lt;/a&gt;. Certainly, fake news is enabled by these technologies. There have been plenty of controversies around their censorship of things, lack of censorship of other things, and generally a great deal of concern about their content moderation &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theverge.com/2019/2/25/18229714/cognizant-facebook-content-moderator-interviews-trauma-working-conditions-arizona&#34;&gt;policies and practices&lt;/a&gt;. The list of societal issues is long, and I won&amp;rsquo;t go all the way into it here. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:11&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Memes</title>
      <link>https://natehn.com/posts/on-memes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://natehn.com/posts/on-memes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This meme repository is presented by&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/0xojO-4VFPw&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A meme is an idea. A trend. A &amp;ldquo;unit of cultural information.&amp;rdquo; Some of my favorite memes are tiny, but dense with content - a juxtaposition of surprising and hilarious images and sounds, crammed into just a short span of time and space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/CMNry4PE93Y&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some were never meant to be funny.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/rY8DSFZ08JQ&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;while others build upon found footage to take it to the next level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/E_dIo1sDA_Q&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of them ask questions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/G7RgN9ijwE4&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(more than once)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/dXidW7fEH8g&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Questions about reality:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/I0DDWJNHLLA&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;about time:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/1Zn958rN-H4&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;and about existence itself:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/fFtgc0CdvJA&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Memes ask &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Q67SozSkzuU&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although they may not have the answers, they still bring us joy, even in the small things:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/jeGTt08xdWA&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like dog ears:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/q8tZIN0GgoI&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Elephant shrews - singing:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Dc6pAuRiyVo&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hilarious pranks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/aMmAsqtGRmk&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And classics that make you crack up EVERY SINGLE TIME.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/EShUeudtaFg&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Thanks for coming to my TED Talk. For more meme content, check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://palmsandpowerlines.substack.com/p/all-star-by-smash-mouth-but-its-my&#34;&gt;my friend Cody&amp;rsquo;s compilation&lt;/a&gt;. You&amp;rsquo;ll never know if you don&amp;rsquo;t  go.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This Website, and How To Build Your Own</title>
      <link>https://natehn.com/posts/this-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://natehn.com/posts/this-website/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;origins&#34;&gt;Origins&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This website is just a bunch of little files living on a tiny computer that sits on my living room bookcase. It plugs into the wall and my router, and all it does all day is serve up these website files to whoever requests them. For most servers out there (shared hosting, virtual private servers, and the like), it is a thankless job. But I try to give my little Lime2 single-board computer some attention every so often. A little bit of gratitude can go a long way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the years, I&amp;rsquo;ve built a few different personal websites. First, there was the college résumé site, &lt;a href=&#34;https://natehn.com/posts/this-website/#origins&#34;&gt;nathanhewitt.net&lt;/a&gt;. Then there were other short-lived iterations: the music-focused &lt;a href=&#34;https://natehn.com/posts/this-website/#origins&#34;&gt;auohm.us&lt;/a&gt; (before I stopped using the moniker AUOHM), the simplistic &lt;a href=&#34;https://natehn.com/posts/this-website/#origins&#34;&gt;nthnh.co&lt;/a&gt;, and the Web 1.0 &lt;a href=&#34;https://natehn.com/posts/this-website/#origins&#34;&gt;omg.lol/nathan&lt;/a&gt;. On the backend, I tried Wordpress, Squarespace, Wix, and others. I also put together plenty of simple, WYSIWYG websites when I was doing freelance graphic design in college.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this website, I originally wanted to self-host in order to learn &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt;. As I built the site, however, I started to come up with other reasons. Over time, a constellation of motivations started to form:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My desire to learn basic Linux programming (&lt;code&gt;bash&lt;/code&gt;) and related technology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trying to get away from corporate-owned social media platforms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finding my written voice again&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experimenting with solar power&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sharing what I have learned; sharing what I am learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Having a home on the web&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Natehn&amp;rdquo; is a new online moniker that mixes three letters of my first and last names. I feel that, as my public engagement with the Internet begins to change, a new name will help to separate the new from the old. (The similarity to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tehn&#34;&gt;Brian Crabtree&amp;rsquo;s moniker&lt;/a&gt; is purely coincidental.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;building-your-own&#34;&gt;Building Your Own&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in building and hosting your own website the way I did, I would be &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:nthnhwtt@gmail.com&#34;&gt;happy to help&lt;/a&gt;. Some basic directions are below. As you go, be sure to also check in on the core documentation for &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.armbian.com/&#34;&gt;Armbian&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/getting-started/quick-start/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;. You may also want to learn the basics of &lt;a href=&#34;https://techlearningcollective.com/foundations/&#34;&gt;the command line&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4d77bxpgB5c&#34;&gt;bash&lt;/a&gt;. Finally, I recommend checking out the guides at &lt;a href=&#34;https://homebrewserver.club/&#34;&gt;the homebrewserver.club&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I made a lot of mistakes along the way - mistakes that hopefully you can avoid. Because of various unforced errors, I ended up trying out three different web server programs (Nginx and Apache, before settling on Caddy) and three different static website builders (Pelican and Jekyll, settling on Hugo). When I was at my wit&amp;rsquo;s end, all I had to do was &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/63351978/css-not-loading-for-self-hosted-nginx-with-jekyll-hugo-site/63359674&#34;&gt;ask for help&lt;/a&gt;. (Thank you @randomsock!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-physical-server&#34;&gt;The Physical Server&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember: there&amp;rsquo;s no such thing as &amp;ldquo;the cloud.&amp;rdquo; There are just a bunch of computers that someone else owns. This one, however, is owned by me. Following the lead of Low←Tech Magazine, I used an &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.olimex.com/wiki/A20-OLinuXino-LIME2&#34;&gt;Olimex Lime2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; running on a variant of Debian (itself a distribution of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linux_distribution&#34;&gt;Linux&lt;/a&gt;) called Armbian. Following Armbian&amp;rsquo;s instructions, I used Balena Etcher to &amp;ldquo;flash&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.armbian.com/olimex-lime-2/&#34;&gt;the image&lt;/a&gt; onto a MicroSD card.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://natehn.com/server.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;My small Olimex server sits amidst my partner&amp;amp;rsquo;s Buddha collection on a bookcase with a LiPo battery zip-tied to the top.&#34;/&gt; &lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;My small Olimex server sits amidst my partner&amp;rsquo;s Buddha collection on a bookcase with a LiPo battery zip-tied to the top.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Insert the MicroSD card, plug in your power adapter, connect it your router with an ethernet cable, connect mouse, keyboard, and HDMI, and you&amp;rsquo;re up and running! After my initial configuration (see below) I always connected to the server via SSH, so there was no need to keep it connected to mouse, keyboard, or monitor.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My basic configuration of the server included logging in as root (pw: 1234) and updating its password, creating a username and password for myself with &lt;code&gt;sudo&lt;/code&gt; admin permissions, logging in, and then making sure everything was up to date via &lt;code&gt;sudo apt-get update &amp;amp;&amp;amp; sudo apt-get upgrade&lt;/code&gt;. I then went ahead and &lt;a href=&#34;https://linuxconfig.org/how-to-setup-a-static-ip-address-on-debian-linux&#34;&gt;set a Static IP (LAN) address&lt;/a&gt; for the Lime2&amp;rsquo;s ethernet port so that it would always be accessible at the same address. I also installed a firewall called UFW and configured it to allow SSH, HTTP, and HTTPS through (&lt;code&gt;sudo ufw allow 22 80 443&lt;/code&gt;). We&amp;rsquo;ll get into more of the networking stuff a little bit later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-static-website&#34;&gt;The Static Website&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Setting up Hugo was simple as could be. I followed &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/getting-started/installing#debian-and-ubuntu&#34;&gt;their directions&lt;/a&gt; to install (&lt;code&gt;sudo apt-get install hugo&lt;/code&gt;). Then I used the Quick Start documentation, creating a directory for my site (&lt;code&gt;mkdir&lt;/code&gt;), &lt;code&gt;cd&lt;/code&gt;-ed into that directory, and created the site using &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/getting-started/quick-start/#step-2-create-a-new-site&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;hugo new site quickstart&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a theme, I am using a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/natehn/blog-theme&#34;&gt;lightly-modified&lt;/a&gt; version of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/monkeyWzr/hugo-theme-cactus&#34;&gt;Cactus&lt;/a&gt;. Hugo has &lt;a href=&#34;https://themes.gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;plenty of themes available&lt;/a&gt;, as well as information on &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/getting-started/quick-start/#step-3-add-a-theme&#34;&gt;how to install them&lt;/a&gt;. All my modifications were done in true amateur fashion - trial and error.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hugo has plenty more information in their Quick Start guide. Once the site was ready, I ran &lt;code&gt;hugo&lt;/code&gt; in the main directory to build the site in a directory called &lt;code&gt;public&lt;/code&gt;. If you&amp;rsquo;ve been following along, your root directory will probably something like &lt;code&gt;home/user/blogfolder/public&lt;/code&gt;. You&amp;rsquo;ll need that info when you set up your webserver.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;networking&#34;&gt;Networking&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make sure that you are ready to receive external traffic, you will need to set up a DCHP reservation and port forwarding (ports 80 and 443) in your router. This basically ensures that folks who connect to your router for the purpose of getting to your website will be directed by the router to your server. The specific process for this will depend on your router and Internet Service Provider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While doing this, go ahead and make a note of the WAN IP Address for your router. You will need this when pointing your domain name at your server. Be aware, unless you set a Static WAN IP address through your Internet Service Provider, it is possible for your WAN address to change. If your website goes down, that could be one of the first things to check.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;your-domain-name&#34;&gt;Your Domain Name&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, of course, you should buy a domain name. Then with your domain name registrar, or wherever you manage the DNS records for your domain, make an A record (a.k.a. &amp;ldquo;address&amp;rdquo; record) pointing to the WAN IP address of your router. The process for doing this depends on your provider. If you are using the same configuration as me, you should also create a URL Redirect record with the hostname &amp;ldquo;www&amp;rdquo; redirecting to the non-www URL of your website (e.g., &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com&#34;&gt;https://example.com&lt;/a&gt;). It can then take 24-48 hours for your new DNS settings to &amp;ldquo;propogate&amp;rdquo; and go into effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-webserver&#34;&gt;The Webserver&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Caddy will be our webserver. To set up Caddy, we will follow the installation directions for Debian put together by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tecmint.com/install-caddy-web-server-in-centos-ubuntu/&#34;&gt;TecMint&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Install Caddy:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;echo &amp;quot;deb [trusted=yes] https://apt.fury.io/caddy/ /&amp;quot; \
    | sudo tee -a /etc/apt/sources.list.d/caddy-fury.list
sudo apt update
sudo apt install caddy
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Start Caddy:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;systemctl start caddy
systemctl enable caddy
systemctl status caddy
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Configure Caddy:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open up the configuration file at &lt;code&gt;/etc/caddy/Caddyfile&lt;/code&gt; with your favorite text editor (e.g., vim, nano). Change &lt;code&gt;:80&lt;/code&gt; to your domain (&lt;code&gt;natehn.com&lt;/code&gt; for example) and the root to the root of your public site, such as &lt;code&gt;home/user/blogfolder/public&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Restart Caddy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Restart Caddy with this new configuration via &lt;code&gt;systemctl reload caddy&lt;/code&gt;. Your website should be up and running!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note Regarding SSL Certificates&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Caddy should take care of your SSL certificate, which is used for HTTPS, automatically on your behalf. If you have trouble with it, check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://certbot.eff.org/lets-encrypt/debianbuster-other&#34;&gt;these instructions from Certbot&lt;/a&gt;. (I did this out of order and got a certificate back when I was using Nginx as my webserver.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;writing&#34;&gt;Writing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For putting posts together, I recommend learning a simple plaintext syntax called Markdown. Hugo uses Markdown to turn plaintext into html.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; It makes writing up an article so much easier. Posts composed using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.markdownguide.org/basic-syntax/&#34;&gt;Markdown&amp;rsquo;s easy syntax&lt;/a&gt; and dropped into blog&amp;rsquo;s directory will become low-weight html pages on your static website. Hugo also has a handy &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/content-management/shortcodes/&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;figure&lt;/code&gt; shortcode&lt;/a&gt; to help you insert images.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://natehn.com/tasman.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;A beautiful sunrise at a campground near Abel Tasman National Park.&#34;/&gt; &lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;A beautiful sunrise at a campground near Abel Tasman National Park.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For focused writing, I use a lightweight plaintext editor called &lt;a href=&#34;https://hundredrabbits.itch.io/left&#34;&gt;Left&lt;/a&gt;, by the awesome sailboatin&amp;rsquo; folks at HundredRabbits. I also use &lt;a href=&#34;https://gottcode.org/focuswriter/&#34;&gt;FocusWriter&lt;/a&gt; on occasion. But any plaintext editor will do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you have a website up and running, you&amp;rsquo;re at the last step: content. In our modern capitalist internet, the content mills never stop running. Blog posts of a certain length, with certain keywords (and questionable value), are used to optimize companies&amp;rsquo; search engine position (the proverbial neverending scramble for &amp;ldquo;SEO&amp;rdquo;). And in this side-hustle culture, it sometimes feels like you have to compete to survive. (I&amp;rsquo;ve certainly felt the pressure before!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to be like this. This site is a start. It is a forum: not content, but discussion - even if it is one-way. A place that is open and honest, especially about imperfections and mistakes. Let&amp;rsquo;s see where it leads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I chose this board based on the recommendation of Low←Tech Magazine and, as they mention, because of all the advantages related to how it is powered. It can provide additional information and can connect directly to a LiPo battery. Along with the board itself, I purchased the case they make for the board and the correct power supply. Separately, I also purchased a 3.7V 6600mAh Lithium Ion battery pack with a JST 2-pin cable attached. Although they say it is a genuine JST connector, I still have trouble disconnecting it sometimes. Not a big deal - I  don&amp;rsquo;t plan to disconnect it often. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On my Windows machine, I use Putty and WinSCP to connect to the Lime2 wirelessly from my computer. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is just simple stuff like changing the copyright line to allow for a Creative Commons license and changing the favicon and logo. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.markdownguide.org/tools/hugo/&#34;&gt;Hugo Markdown Support&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
